<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">Read the Docs Blog - Posts tagged open source</title>
  <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/open-source/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2015-05-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com" />
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/open-source/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <generator uri="http://ablog.readthedocs.org" version="0.9.5">ABlog</generator>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/open-source/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Fundraising Wrapup</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/fundraising-wrapup/</id>
    <updated>2015-05-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-05-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/fundraising-wrapup/" />
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;fundraising-wrapup&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, a big ol’ thank you is in order for everyone that helped support us.
You all helped us hit our funding goal, and with time to spare.  We’re humbled
to have such an abundance of support, and to know so many people share our
vision for great documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, thank you all. ❤&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started the fund raise drive at the beginning of PyCon, and in a little under
3 weeks you were able to bring us up to our funding goal of $24,000. With the
end of April, we’ve wrapped up fundraising for now. You can &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.org/sustainability/&quot;&gt;still contribute&lt;/a&gt;
however, and give us a head start on our next fund raising goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We set our goal to cover support costs for the next 3 months, and to set Read
the Docs on a path to becoming self-sustaining. It will allow us to dedicate
time to supporting and maintaining the service as it continues to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, we’ve had &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.org/sustainability/#supporters&quot;&gt;157 contributions&lt;/a&gt;, and we couldn’t have hit our goal
without the help of everyone. The Python Software Foundation graciously provided
us with a grant for $8,000 to go towards the continued support efforts.  Our
largest corporate sponsors include &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://twilio.com&quot;&gt;Twilio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://getsentry.com&quot;&gt;Sentry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://dreamhost.com&quot;&gt;DreamHost&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://lincolnloop.com&quot;&gt;Lincoln Loop&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, we have received generous service sponsorships
from &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://elastic.co&quot;&gt;Elastic Search&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://maxcdn.com&quot;&gt;MaxCDN&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://gandi.net&quot;&gt;Gandi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, a huge thank you to everyone that made this happen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;what-to-expect&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What to Expect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are building a company around an open source service, and we strive to remain
open about what we’re doing. As a first step, we will be documenting how our
time is used up and how we are allocating funds for the costs. We will be
providing updates on our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://trello.com/b/tF04aNrT/read-the-docs-public&quot;&gt;public Trello board&lt;/a&gt;, we welcome you to
subscribe for updates and to provide us with feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funds will go towards covering the support and maintenance costs of Read the
Docs each week. We want to increase our capacity to handle support requests by
working with someone on a part-time contract basis, working solely on managing
this support burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each week, the funds will pay for up to 40 hours of time spent supporting the
service.  We look to cover triaging support requests and operations maintenance
and emergency support with this time. Time will be split up between several
engineers, we hope to cover part of the week with our time and the majority of
the time each week with a third set of hands. Development will continue as a
community supported mechanism, with the time of the core team donated to the
project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
