<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">Read the Docs Blog - Posts tagged report</title>
  <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/report/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2015-09-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com" />
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/report/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <generator uri="http://ablog.readthedocs.org" version="0.9.5">ABlog</generator>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/report/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">State of the Docs</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/state-of-the-docs-2015/</id>
    <updated>2015-09-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-09-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/state-of-the-docs-2015/" />
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;state-of-the-docs&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August has historical significance for Read the Docs, so it seemed fitting to
wrap up August by taking a moment to step back and reflect on what we’ve done in
the last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What makes August so significant for us?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, this August saw the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://ericholscher.com/blog/2010/aug/16/announcing-read-docs/&quot;&gt;5th birthday of Read the Docs&lt;/a&gt;!
We’re still humbled by the project’s success, and the important role it
continues to play for old and new users alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This growth was becoming difficult to manage without focused support given back
to the community. Though the project has always had core maintainers, for Read
the Docs to continue growing as a community resource, we knew it required
dedicated attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the reason why, in August of last year, Eric and I set out to create a
company around Read the Docs – another significant bookmark in Read the Docs’
history. We planned to build the company to fund the ongoing support efforts of
the community site and to help accelerate its growth. At this time last year, we
had just formed Read the Docs, Inc, we were fresh into the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://piepdx.com&quot;&gt;PIE accelerator
program&lt;/a&gt;, and we were planning how to bring our documentation values to
companies that weren’t open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;the-last-year&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The last year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our primary goal has always been to drive the development of our community site,
with hopes that it would one day be self-sustaining. We made a number of
decisions and changes to work towards this goal in the last year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Treat the community site as a separate entity&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to be independently sustainable, the community site needs income of
its own. The service is large enough now that dedicated staff is a
necessity. There needs to be someone to drive development, handle support
requests, and be accountable for keeping everything running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, all money coming into Read the Docs is treated as income into the
business. We do track income to the community site separately, so we can
budget for the community site separately from running the rest of the
business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aren’t yet to the point where this split is critical. There are no
employees of the business yet, and we are only able to pay ourselves for a
small portion of the work we perform for the community site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will need to track this explicitly as we grow however, as the community
site will need to rely on donations for the foreseeable future. Those
donations should not go towards developing the for-profit side directly.
Development of the community site will still be a primary function of income
into the for-profit side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the community site could be structured completely separate, to
provide a more explicit split.  It could probably be structured as a 501c,
This doesn’t make financial sense yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Our support fundraiser&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an effort to fund development and maintenance on the community site, we
decided to call on our community for financial support back in June.  This
was the first time we have asked the community for contributions.  Our goal
was to fund at least a portion of the time spent developing and supporting
the community site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all the contributors from our community, we raised our goal of
$24,000, and were able to fund the time of multiple engineers working
steadily on Read the Docs for the last few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already outlined our costs and our plans behind our June fundraiser in a
previous post. We will be following up the last few months of work with an
overall review of the fundraiser and the work we performed in the coming
weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Triaging&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, our support responsiveness has been more apparent.  One hurdle in
bringing on more engineers, and engaging the community more, was the lack of
formal ticketing and open decision making.  Gregor, among many other
changes, laid out a formal triage process that has been a major influence in
keeping an organized and healthy support queue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve definitely found that the more support engagement we provide the
community, the more support comes out of the woodwork.  This is all part of
supporting a healthy community however, as we have learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Stability&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Read the Docs has “grown organically”, which is to say it has grown fast,
unwieldy, and in many directions.  With more proper focus on code quality,
including clean up efforts, refactoring, and long due upgrades, Read the
Docs has shed considerable technical debt in the last couple months.  This
work has already paid off in improving stability and predictability of the
project.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Ads&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;We ran a few tests with advertising on built documentation in the last few
months.  We discussed at length how we felt about ads and determined our own
problems with the standard implementation of ads is not the ads themselves,
but the breach of privacy they signify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of that, we established that a requirement of us ever showing ads is
to not use third party tracking.  In fact, we look to remove all third party
tracking from built documentation as soon as we can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put ads into a clearer context, revenue from in-house ads fully cover our
costs each month, without asking the community for any further support. It
probably shouldn’t be surprising that advertising revenue is an easier
income source than seeking donations. We certainly feel Read the Docs
provides more value than the ads it would serve though. Our last fundraiser
reflected the value the community puts on the site, and we hope the next
fundraiser can be as successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should we ever use ads as a primary revenue source for the community site,
we have established some rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will provide our ads in-house, not through any service that establishes
third party tracking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will not sell any data about our users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will always prefer ad sponsorship from community members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users that support us through donations or sponsorship are opt out of ads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback regarding ads has been positive, hopefully our intentions with ads
has been mostly apparent. We’ll be discussing our thoughts on advertising in
more depth soon, if you have any feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Gold&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve begun working on a “gold” status feature for users that want to
support us each month. This will be an optional, recurring subscription to
Read the Docs. The subscription will provide some additional features for
users or projects, and some advanced project features might suggest a gold
subscription for projects that make use of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea is still evolving, we’ll be asking for more feedback as this
feature matures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;the-next-year&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The next year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, let us now set some expectations for the next year forward:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Transparency and feedback&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;Operating in the open has been an important tenant to our company since
formation.  We believe whole-heartedly in the trust and candid feedback it
provides, and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.opencompany.org/about/&quot;&gt;we have pledged&lt;/a&gt; to keep openness and transparency
at the core of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the structure that has guided us as a company has been providing
updates to those that we are accountable to. During our time at PIE, this
was to our mentors and our peers. Now, we want to be accountable to you, our
community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to continue the periodic updates that started with the
fundraiser, and we plan on releasing updates, on a quarterly basis, that
share more insights into the company.  We will continue to expose our goals,
problems, and decisions to you as we grow and we hope you can provide us
with your feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Continued work towards stability&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We still have some technical debt that will take a while to pay off,
but ensuring stability is paramount to having a service we can all rely on.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Support responsiveness&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We will adhere as much as we can to the processes that we established around
our support channels. We hope that these processes will also allow others in
the community to easily fill these roles should we need the help.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for our technical goals, outside our roadmap and continued cleanup and
maintenance, here is what we have on our roadmap:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;User experience&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;With components becoming more stable, and a generally more stable code base,
we are shifting focus towards user experience – the pieces most obvious to
users. We’ve made some gains here in the past few months, but have a ways to
go still.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Easier documentation build tools&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Sphinx is an incredibly powerful tool, but for new users this can be
overwhelming. We are developing tooling to ease this process for new users
and provide a solid footing for the majority of use cases. This will also
help to make the build process more predictable, as this would mimic our
build backend processes closely.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;More reference doc language support&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We have been working towards wider language support for generating API
reference documentation. Most recently, we worked with Microsoft to develop
support for &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/sphinxcontrib-dotnetdomain&quot;&gt;.NET language support in Sphinx&lt;/a&gt;. This allows
authors to use existing .NET tooling to generate reStructuredText API
reference documentation.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;let-us-know&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let us know&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any feedback or opinions on any of this, continue to let us know.
We’re happy to have the feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/report/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Report - July 2015</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/report-july-2015/</id>
    <updated>2015-09-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-09-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/report-july-2015/" />
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;report-july-2015&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August was a hectic month for us. So busy, in fact, we never wrote this update.
We dropped the ball on getting this report out on time, but hope to keep on top
of future updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July was a month of stability fixes, with some substantial changes to our
infrastructure. First, here’s an update on some of the goals we had set with
our last monthly update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Improve Github/Bitbucket integration&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;This got pushed to next month, we didn’t focus on this as much as we had
hoped.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Test internal analytics&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have a basic testbed for internal analytics set up, but haven’t gone as
far as pushing this integration into production. We still need to test
production load and what the dataset would look like over the course of a
month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is on hold for the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also set some additional goals near the beginning of the month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Finish rolling out a new stack&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our servers were all reasonably aged and have not been re-provisioned in a
long while. We set the goal to move all configuration to configuration
management and be able to reproduce servers in a predictable manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were able to finish moving all provisioning to configuration management
and rolled out all new servers, including some new servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Improve monitoring&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have hit a lot of common cases that we should be tracking as part of our
standard operations notifications. We set the goal to improve our
notification and debugging capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With fresh provisioning, we now also have a programmatic approach towards
setting up system checks and notifications, and have expanded our reporting
a great deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;update-details&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Update Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;ops&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ops&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Fresh web servers&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Last month, we rolled out fresh build servers, strictly using configuration
management to provision servers. This month, we continued by moving web
server provision to our configuration management and re-rolling all of our
web servers.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Fresh database servers and migration&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also rolled new database servers, and took the opportunity to upgrade our
database’s PostgreSQL instance and perform some needed schema changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to perform the migration late one evening, when our then primary
database server was included in an outage of some Rackspace infrastructure.
The outage resulted in some extended downtime, and we were not immediately
able to migrate data from the database server to the fresh instance. The
outage resolved early in the morning and migration wrapped shortly after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new instance performed better than expected, once we made it live.  The
fresh instance had more memory and increased bandwidth for disk operations.
Along with a reindex of a table with slow queries, we noticed significant
reduction in query times and a great improvement of stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Improved monitoring&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We started to catch some edge cases that were not previously monitored and
improved greatly on our monitoring and graphing.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;dev&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dev&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Django 1.8 upgrade&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Our previous version of Django was on the now unsupported 1.6 branch. With
1.8 released, we felt it was a great chance to finally upgrade our
dependencies.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Triage process&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We have formalized our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://docs.readthedocs.org/en/latest/contribute.html#triaging-tickets&quot;&gt;triage process&lt;/a&gt; for development. This will guide
how we make decisions on our issue tracker.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Linting&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Linting has not been performed on the codebase for a long while. We felt
this was important to get back to in order to ensure code quality.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Stable version improvements&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;There has been some buggy behavior behind the stable version detection. We
worked here to clean up some of the broken behavior.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Fix slugging on versions&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;There have been a number of error cases that have surfaced around version
slugging recently. This works to fix some logic errors on edge cases.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on our development orchestration, visit or subscribe to our
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://trello.com/b/tF04aNrT/read-the-docs-public&quot;&gt;public Trello board&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;issues&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the month of July:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the Docs saw &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=created%3A2015-07-01..2015-07-31+type%3Aissue&quot;&gt;80 new issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50 of those issues &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=created%3A2015-07-01..2015-07-31+type%3Aissue+state%3Aclosed&quot;&gt;have been closed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=created%3A%3C2015-07-01+type%3Aissue+state%3Aclosed+closed%3A2015-07-01..2015-07-31&quot;&gt;35 outstanding issues&lt;/a&gt; were closed out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to raise any questions you have about any of these changes on our
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues&quot;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;, or on our Freenode IRC channel, #readthedocs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;goals-for-next-month&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals for Next Month&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Improve Github/Bitbucket integration&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We have pushed this up to next month, we still need to address some failures
as part of Github/Bitbucket integration.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Better Sphinx experience for authoring&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We can streamline a lot of the experience around using Sphinx, and at the
same time, make more reproduceable builds, locally, for authors. This would
involve mimicking more of what we preform in our build backend for local
authoring.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;More code cleanup&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We started some linting efforts to bring code quality up, we will continue
deeper and more thorough linting efforts.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;More features to user gold subscription&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We would like to have more users on a recurring subscription, which is a
great step towards sustainability. We should be surfacing features and
reminding users to donate if they are using some of those features.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/report/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Report - August 2015</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/report-august-2015/</id>
    <updated>2015-09-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-09-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/report-august-2015/" />
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;report-august-2015&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August was a busy month for us. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.writethedocs.org/conf/eu/2015/&quot;&gt;Write the Docs Europe&lt;/a&gt; was at the end of the
month, and our focus has been on getting &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.com&quot;&gt;readthedocs.com&lt;/a&gt; into a
public beta state. We’re nearing the end of the 3 month period that we budgeted
for as part of our fundraiser and have a few more tasks to push out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;goals&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, an update of the goals we set for this month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Improve Github/Bitbucket integration&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We fixed a very common bug caused by the way implemented syncing to the
Github API. There are still some user experience issues we would like to
address.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Better Sphinx experience for authoring&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We started to refactor parts of our build backend and discussed what the
optimal tool for authors would be. We don’t have a clear sense of where to
split up our build backend code and what is extraneous to authors yet,
however.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;More code cleanup&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Linting cleanup progressed, and we are on to discussing stricter linting
efforts.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;More features to user gold subscription&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We have added the ability to “bless” projects with a gold subscription, but
are still working on the user experience behind reminding users to donate
via gold subscriptions, nor are we explaining gold to users yet.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;update-details&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Update Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Build backend refactor&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;The builder backend code was refactored and now all build commands executed
are tracked and associated with builds. This surfaced a number of hidden
commands and a few failure conditions that were being disregarded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also removes the confusing magic PDF build that gets triggered from a
normal build object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Build output page&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;With the build refactor tracking all commands separately, we can now show
output of all the commands executed. Before this output was split into
output and error output streams, and it wasn’t always easy to distinguish
failures. The build output page will now also live update through the API as
changes become available.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Improved Github Syncing&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Our initial attempt at Github integration updated from the Github API
in-process, which could result in a timeout when the API didn’t return quick
enough. Syncing against the API was moved to our task queue, with an API to
monitor changes to the task.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Started work on more automated build toolchain&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We have plans to make the process for building Sphinx documentation more
automated for authors. We started laying out plans for what that tool would
look like and how it would function.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on our development orchestration, visit or subscribe to our
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://trello.com/b/tF04aNrT/read-the-docs-public&quot;&gt;public Trello board&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;issues&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the month of August:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the Docs saw &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=created%3A2015-08-01..2015-08-31+type%3Aissue&quot;&gt;55 new issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;36 of those issues &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=created%3A2015-08-01..2015-08-31+type%3Aissue+state%3Aclosed&quot;&gt;have been closed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=created%3A%3C2015-08-01+type%3Aissue+state%3Aclosed+closed%3A2015-08-01..2015-08-31&quot;&gt;59 outstanding issues&lt;/a&gt; were closed out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to raise any questions you have about any of these changes on our
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues&quot;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;, or on our Freenode IRC channel, #readthedocs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;goals-for-next-month&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals for Next Month&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Improve gold subscriptions more&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;With the fundraiser funds nearly allocated, we need to begin budgeting for
the next few months, and will need to start bringing in income. We want to
improve the user experience around donating, as well as present more
reminders to donate to active users.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Increase income for the community site&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;With better user experience around donating, we hope to launch another
effort to get more users and companies to donate.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Improve import user experience&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;There are still some gritty parts to the import process that should be
streamlined. Some of the major Github bugs have been squashed, but a larger
UX improvement is still required.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/report/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Report - June 2015</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/report-june-2015/</id>
    <updated>2015-07-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2015-07-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/report-june-2015/" />
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;report-june-2015&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://writethedocs.org&quot;&gt;Write the Docs&lt;/a&gt; conference wrapped up in May, we shifted our focus
back to Read the Docs for the remainder of May and June. Following our post
&lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../read-the-docs-is-hiring/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;on contract positions available&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with Read the
Docs, we hired two contractors to work with us and focus on support and
stability for readthedocs.org. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/gregmuellegger&quot;&gt;Gregor Müllegger&lt;/a&gt; will be working on support
and development, and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/onewheelskyward&quot;&gt;Andrew Kreps&lt;/a&gt; has helped us on building and improving our
operations infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;updates&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the Docs had the following major updates in June:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;ops&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ops&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elastic Search support was upgraded and our search cluster is now hosted on
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://found.no&quot;&gt;Found&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We greatly improved the Read the Docs infrastructure, including monitoring and alerting, as well as server
environment consistency. Using Nagios and Graphite, as well as Salt, for this task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static assets were migrated to use a CDN, provided by &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://maxcdn.com&quot;&gt;MaxCDN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We did a fresh provision of our build cluster using Salt. Previously, there were slight
disparities between the servers, which surfaced some issues during builds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed Python 3 build environments with new virtualenv and pip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed our queueing strategy to not be tied to a single specific build machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;dev&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dev&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Output formats such as PDF and ePub are now configurable, but continue to default
to on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the ability to wipe the Build environment to the Versions page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We started to address issues with stable version detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issues related to version name slugging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In order to move away from third party analytics, we have spun up an instance
of Piwik. We plan on testing this with our production traffic in the coming months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed “Edit on GitHub” links for stable versions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General refactoring and cleanup of the codebase, and added test coverage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on our development orchestration, visit or subscribe to our
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://trello.com/b/tF04aNrT/read-the-docs-public&quot;&gt;public Trello board&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;issues&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have started to formalize on a ticket triage process and have more focus on
performing project management in the open. This is a very welcome change to our
existing workflow and hope to continue improving on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the month of June:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the Docs saw &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=created%3A2015-06-01..2015-06-30+type%3Aissue&quot;&gt;50 new issues&lt;/a&gt; in the month of June&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;26 of those issues &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=created%3A2015-06-01..2015-06-30+type%3Aissue+state%3Aclosed&quot;&gt;have been closed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=created%3A2015-06-01..2015-06-30+type%3Aissue+state%3Aopen&quot;&gt;The remaining 24&lt;/a&gt; have been triaged but remain unresolved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;amp;q=created%3A%3C2015-06-01+type%3Aissue+state%3Aclosed+closed%3A2015-06-01..2015-06-30&quot;&gt;19 outstanding issues&lt;/a&gt; were closed out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;next-month&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Next Month&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once work is wrapped up on version detection cleanup, we hope to start
improving our Github/Bitbucket integration and user experience
issues around deleting old projects and versions from Read the Docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also be testing internal analytics in the coming months. Our stance is
that user data, for both our users and for readers of hosted documentation,
should not be handed over to third party services like Google Analytics. We hope
to replace external analytics with an internally hosted service, so that your
data remains with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to raise any questions you have about any of these changes on our
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues&quot;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;, or on our Freenode IRC channel, #readthedocs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
