<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">Read the Docs Blog - Posts from San Diego, CA</title>
  <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/san-diego-ca/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2020-07-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com" />
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/san-diego-ca/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <generator uri="http://ablog.readthedocs.org" version="0.9.5">ABlog</generator>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/san-diego-ca/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Advertising update and open sourcing our ad server</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/advertising-improvements-2020/</id>
    <updated>2020-07-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2020-07-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/advertising-improvements-2020/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;advertising-update-and-open-sourcing-our-ad-server&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since our &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../ad-funding-read-the-docs-whats-next/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;last advertising update&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
and it felt like a good time to talk about what’s working with our advertising model
and how things are getting better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;how-advertising-is-working-for-read-the-docs&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How advertising is working for Read the Docs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../read-the-docs-2019-stats/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;2019 stats post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
we broke out our advertising revenue which was fairly flat year over year.
The way our ad business is structured, our revenue mostly grows with increases in traffic
and Read the Docs is mature enough that it isn’t doubling in size every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that said, we’re pleased with our steady and sustainable growth.
Read the Docs doesn’t have any investors putting pressure on us for short term growth
and that has allowed us to invest in our ad business, commercial hosting,
and in our community version for the long term.
We’ve rolled out a huge number of improvements to all the sides of our business
in the last year and we’re happy with the results.
Advertising remains the single largest source of funding for Read the Docs
and one that scales as our costs scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a real world note, Covid-19 had a short term impact on our advertising revenue
with a number of advertisers understandably pulling back due to uncertainty in funding and the economy in general.
While the world isn’t completely back to normal, we have returned some degree of normalcy
and most of these advertisers returned once there was a bit more clarity in the broader economy
and the virus’ effect on the tech industry specifically.
Advertising on Read the Docs is now close to capacity in the US, Canada, and Europe which are our largest advertising markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;improved-targeting-for-ads&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improved targeting for ads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertising on Read the Docs is different from most ad networks out there.
Our ad targeting is based on the content and the reader’s geography rather than personal data about our users.
Read the Docs’ authors and readers have told us that privacy is important to them.
That’s great because it’s important to us too!
With that said, there are great ways to target specific content niches with ads relevant to those readers without compromising on privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start, we chose a few groups of content advertisers can target where we have enough traffic
without the ads being focused on a tiny number of projects.
These niches are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data science and machine learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frontend web development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backend web development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DevOps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tested this improved content targeting with a select group of advertisers and the results were great.
In some cases we saw click through rates more than double.
Whether the ad is to hire a developer or to promote a service,
we always want to deliver ads that are most relevant to the documentation being served.
This results in better value to our advertisers
while still respecting the privacy of our readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;admonition-would-your-company-like-to-get-in-front-of-more-developers admonition&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;first admonition-title&quot;&gt;Would your company like to get in front of more developers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;last&quot;&gt;Tell your &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.org/sustainability/advertising/?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=readthedocs-blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=ethical-advertising-2020&quot;&gt;marketing or recruiting team&lt;/a&gt; about Read the Docs
and show them how they can reach over 7 million developers who Read the Docs each month!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;open-sourcing-our-ad-server&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Open sourcing our ad server&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing we’ve wanted to do for a long time is open source the code
we use to run advertising at Read the Docs.
While there’s always a bit of an incentive to keep advertising code closed so it can’t be abused,
our hope is that the trust we’re building with the ethical ads model
can be used by others who want to run their own ethical advertising.
Read the Docs is an open source company and it’s nice to have all our code out there.
We call it the ethical ad server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ethical ad server is built to handle the kind of load Read the Docs itself receives
– over a million hits per day –
and it delivers advertising based only on content and geographic targeting
rather than building up user profiles from personal information.
It’s built from the ground up with user privacy in mind.
We’re excited to share it with you so please &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/readthedocs/ethical-ad-server&quot;&gt;check out the code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as we’re constantly delivering improvements to Read the Docs itself for our readers and project maintainers,
we also strive to give a better experience and better results to the companies who trust Read the Docs as a marketing channel.
I want to thank all our advertisers who believe in our approach and continue to support us
and stay tuned to this space for more great features in the future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ethical ad network is just about ready for launch
and we’re actively looking for projects to beta test the network.
If you run a developer focused website and you’re looking for a way to earn money
without selling out your visitors’ privacy,
please &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:ads&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;readthedocs&amp;#46;org?subject=Ethical%20Ad%20Network%20beta&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/san-diego-ca/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Optimizing Sphinx Documentation for Search Engines</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/seo-for-technical-docs/</id>
    <updated>2019-08-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-08-29T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/seo-for-technical-docs/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;optimizing-sphinx-documentation-for-search-engines&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, we published a guide on &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/guides/technical-docs-seo-guide.html&quot;&gt;SEO for technical docs&lt;/a&gt;
with the goal of helping documentation authors and project maintainers create docs
so that end users can find what they’re looking for easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One developer asked me point blank after I mentioned our new guide,
“Hasn’t Google closed most of the loopholes that sites use to rank better?”.
I’ve heard this opinion from a few technologists before so I wasn’t too surprised.
Moz.com, an authority on search engine optimization,
makes a distinction between what they call &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://moz.com/blog/black-hat-or-white-hat-seo-ask-better-questions&quot;&gt;black hat SEO and white hat SEO&lt;/a&gt;
to differentiate between these “loopholes” and more useful site improvements that help SEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Black hat SEO is basically a set of tactics some sites use to improve rankings
without actually making their site better to end visitors.
This includes techniques like displaying different content to search engines (cloaking),
link farming, or adding semi-relevant keywords into a page (keyword stuffing).
When Google and Bing discover a site doing this,
they take action and lower a site’s ranking until the problems are fixed.
Black hat SEO is inherently risky and we try to stay away from this kind of SEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead our guide focuses on white hat SEO which aims to improve your docs’ search engine rankings
by helping search engine’s understand and index your docs better and present it better to searchers.
This kind of SEO isn’t trying to cheat search engine rankings and it’s a win for everyone.
Searchers find the content they’re looking for more easily
while search engines understand the content better and can show more relevant results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, we also tried to focus on SEO for documentation
and how Sphinx and Read the Docs make it easier including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making your docs display better on search engine results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helping search engines understand and index your docs better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving your ranking based on user and search engine feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;making-your-docs-display-better-in-search-results&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making your docs display better in search results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure align-center&quot; id=&quot;id1&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot;&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;_static/google-search-engine-results.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;_static/google-search-engine-results.png&quot; src=&quot;_static/google-search-engine-results.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Google search engine results with the page title, URL, and a description.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Displaying more relevant information in search results will cause more people to click through to your docs.
Again, your goal is not to use cheap tactics to rank better and trick users into clicking.
Rather, you are trying to legitimately improve your content such that users
better understand what to expect on a page before they click.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the most important aspects of improved search listings are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use descriptive and accurate titles in the HTML &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag.
With Sphinx, the &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; comes from the top heading on the page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure your URLs are descriptive. They are displayed in search results.
For Sphinx, the URL uses the source file’s filename.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure the words your readers would search for to find your site
are actually included on your pages.
Ideally, these key words should be in your &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; or description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These concepts are not only important in helping guide users to click on your documentation,
most of the same optimizations are useful to the search engine when indexing your site
and when ranking your site for searchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;helping-search-engines-understand-your-docs&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Helping search engines understand your docs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search engines like Google and Bing crawl through the internet
following links and redirects in an attempt to understand and build an index
of what various pages and sites are about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These tips and features can help you control how search engines index your docs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure your entire site can be navigated by following links.
If you have “orphan” pages, a search engine won’t find them.
Using Sphinx’s “toctree” directive helps make sure all your pages are indexed and navigable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redirects and canonical URLs are useful when the same content exists in multiple places
or moves from one page to another.
Read the Docs dashboard lets authors setup redirects from one page to another
or from one version of the documentation to another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;robots.txt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;sitemap.xml&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; file can help you control how search engines crawl your docs.
For example, you could tell search engines to ignore unsupported versions of your documentation.
Read the Docs provides both a &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;robots.txt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; and a sitemap and has ways for you to override them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;improving-your-seo-ranking-from-feedback&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improving your SEO ranking from feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search engines provide tools to help webmasters build their site better
and to give insights and feedback about the indexing of sites by the search engine spiders.
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://search.google.com/search-console&quot;&gt;Google Search Console&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bing.com/webmaster/help/webmaster-guidelines-30fba23a&quot;&gt;Bing Webmaster Tools&lt;/a&gt;
are tools for webmasters
to get feedback about the crawling of their sites (or docs in our case).
These tools can show technical issues with indexing like pages that are failing for some reason
and also possible security or spam issues on your site that can lower your ranking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure align-center&quot; id=&quot;id2&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot;&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external image-reference&quot; href=&quot;_static/google-search-console.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;_static/google-search-console.png&quot; src=&quot;_static/google-search-console.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Google search console showing an issue with user generated spam, a constant battle at Read the Docs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback on keywords users use to find your docs is also really helpful.
This is true both for the phrases people searched for on a search engine
and for the search terms people queried in Sphinx and Read the Docs’ built-in search features.
Analytics tools like Google Analytics can provide these insights,
but as part of our &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../improved-search-and-search-as-you-type/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;search improvements and search analytics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
Read the Docs is going to show project maintainers the most common search queries to help them improve as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;seo-is-no-substitute-for-good-writing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SEO is no substitute for good writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One area we didn’t detail in our guide is how more general improvements to technical writing
can also improve your search engine rankings. This could be a whole post by itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using simpler words, for example, has a number of advantages in technical writing.
The excellent Microsoft Style Guide &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/style-guide/word-choice/use-simple-words-concise-sentences&quot;&gt;recommends using simple words and concise sentences&lt;/a&gt;
and Apple’s Style Guide &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://help.apple.com/applestyleguide/#/apsg1ff68ab5&quot;&gt;echoes the same sentiment&lt;/a&gt;.
Simpler sentences are easier to understand for both people
as well as machines like search engines and automatic translators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While any style guide you read will tell you to avoid using jargon,
technical writing and software docs have a certain amount of unavoidable technical terminology.
Defining these terms and phrases when you first use them helps users as well as search engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;in-summary&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always keep in mind that your ultimate goal is to make your docs more discoverable by people, not machines.
While the concepts and tactics here will help you rank better with search engines,
providing high quality documentation and making it easier to find and understand
is the best way to make sure people actually read the docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/san-diego-ca/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Adding Custom CSS or JavaScript to Sphinx Documentation</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/custom-css-and-js-in-sphinx/</id>
    <updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-07-10T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/custom-css-and-js-in-sphinx/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;adding-custom-css-or-javascript-to-sphinx-documentation&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Read the Docs documentation, we have a number of
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/page/guides/index.html&quot;&gt;how-to guides&lt;/a&gt;
to help people solve specific problems with Sphinx and Read the Docs.
By far our most popular guide is on
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/page/guides/adding-custom-css.html&quot;&gt;adding custom CSS and JavaScript to Sphinx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some older versions of Sphinx, this process was a little more challenging
and it wasn’t as easy to figure out how to do it from the Sphinx docs.
Sphinx 1.8 really streamlined this process especially for the simple cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;adding-additional-stylesheets-or-scripts&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Adding additional stylesheets or scripts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your custom stylesheet is &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;_static/css/custom.css&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;,
you can add that CSS file to the documentation using the
Sphinx option &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.sphinx-doc.org/page/usage/configuration.html#confval-html_css_files&quot;&gt;html_css_files&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight-python notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;## conf.py&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# These folders are copied to the documentation&amp;#39;s HTML output&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;html_static_path&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;_static&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# These paths are either relative to html_static_path&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# or fully qualified paths (eg. https://...)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;html_css_files&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;css/custom.css&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar approach can be used to add JavaScript files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight-python notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;html_js_files&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;js/custom.js&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it!
You don’t need to create a Sphinx extension anymore to add a bit of custom CSS or JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;customizations-supported-by-your-theme&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Customizations supported by your theme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should also note that depending on the theme you’re using and what you’re hoping to accomplish,
you may not even need to add custom CSS or JavaScript.
Many themes support a number of “theme options”
for customizing their look and feel without having to write custom code.
For example, here are all the options for the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://sphinx-rtd-theme.readthedocs.io/page/configuring.html&quot;&gt;Read the Docs theme&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://alabaster.readthedocs.io/page/customization.html&quot;&gt;Alabaster theme&lt;/a&gt;
which are the two most popular themes on Read the Docs itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both themes, for example, support the addition of Google Analytics to documentation by setting the &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;analytics_id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; option:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight-python notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;## conf.py&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;html_theme_options&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;analytics_id&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;UA-XXXXXXX-1&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#  Provided in your GA dashboard&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;in-summary&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To recap, it only takes a few additions to your &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;conf.py&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; to add custom CSS or JavaScript.
However, it’s also worth taking a look at your theme’s docs or &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.sphinx-doc.org/page/usage/configuration.html#options-for-html-output&quot;&gt;Sphinx’s built-in HTML options&lt;/a&gt;
to see if what you’re trying to do is already supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy documenting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/san-diego-ca/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">New Ad Format Coming to Read the Docs Community Sites</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/fixed-footer-ad-all-themes/</id>
    <updated>2019-06-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-06-18T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/fixed-footer-ad-all-themes/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;new-ad-format-coming-to-read-the-docs-community-sites&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We view our ad program as a way to keep Read the Docs itself sustainable,
and to use it to better support the community.
Advertising has allowed us to have full-time employees adding new features
and responding to issues in our issue tracker.
We have also been able to share thousands of dollars with the open source community
via our revenue share program and grants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, about 30% of our site traffic does not have any advertising.
When we first launched ethical advertising in 2016,
we launched only on &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../ads-on-other-themes/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;specific documentation themes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
We purposely did this slowly to make sure our ads look integrated
with Read the Docs and less obtrusive to users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while, this wasn’t a problem because we had not reached capacity with advertising.
We did not have enough paid advertisers to support the amount of pageviews Read the Docs served.
Fast forward a couple years,
and our advertising model has &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../ad-funding-read-the-docs-whats-next/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;proven to be successful&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
In North America and Western Europe,
&lt;strong&gt;100% of pages that are eligible for paid advertising have a paid ad&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve hit that limit, it makes sense to expand to more themes.
Rather than going theme by theme as we did in the past,
especially considering the huge number of Sphinx themes,
we designed an ad that would work across all Sphinx themes.
This became much easier with a more simple text-only ad as you will see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be very explicit,
&lt;strong&gt;this new ad format will show advertising on all documentation themes&lt;/strong&gt;.
We plan to roll this new ad format out more widely in stages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To start with, we are going to enable this ad format for community and house advertising
on pages that already have ads on them.
As always, we never display two ads on the same page so this ad will be instead of any other ad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After that, we will allow paid advertisers to use this new format.
Again, we will start only on pages that already have ads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will email users of custom documentation themes to let them know this change is coming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At first, we will show only community and house ads on these custom themes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, we’ll turn on our normal ad rotation to all themes.
We expect to complete this by the end of July.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will closely monitor feedback from document authors, readers, and advertisers during this process.
If you have questions or comments on this, please &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:ads&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;readthedocs&amp;#46;org?subject=New%20Ad%20Format%20Feedback&quot;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;text-only-ads&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Text-only ads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve wanted to try text-only ads for a while but it took time to get it right.
From the start, we were very keen on text-only advertisements
because they aren’t as obtrusive as image-based ads
and they are easier for advertisers to create and experiment with multiple variations.
What we didn’t know was whether users would engage with them at similar rates to our other ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ran a small experiment with a text-only house ad
on the Read the Docs documentation itself and the results were very promising.
Engagement rates were over double our site average
and even compared favorably with the same ad in the sidebar including an image.
Those figures may not hold up as the format is rolled out more widely but it is certainly a good sign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure align-default&quot; id=&quot;id1&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;A text-only ad on the Read the Docs documentation. Yes, this new format will be blocked by most ad blockers.&quot; src=&quot;img/2019-text-only-ad.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 80%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;A text-only footer advertisement on the Read the Docs documentation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to thank Eric Berry over at &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://codefund.io/&quot;&gt;CodeFund&lt;/a&gt; for some great ideas
and insights around this kind of ad format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;opting-out&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Opting Out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We understand that advertising doesn’t work for everyone – even advertising without any user tracking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can opt-out of paid advertising themselves and for any projects they maintain
although they will still see community ads for open source projects and conferences.
Gold members of Read the Docs get an ad-free experience
and for companies we have our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.com/&quot;&gt;commercial offering at readthedocs.com&lt;/a&gt;
which is always ad-free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to completely remove advertising from your open source project,
but our commercial plans don’t seem like the right fit,
please &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:ads&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;readthedocs&amp;#46;org?subject=Alternatives%20to%20advertising&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; to discuss alternatives to advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/san-diego-ca/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Ad Funding at Read the Docs and What’s Next for Ethical Advertising</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/ad-funding-read-the-docs-whats-next/</id>
    <updated>2019-06-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-06-11T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/ad-funding-read-the-docs-whats-next/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;ad-funding-at-read-the-docs-and-what-s-next-for-ethical-advertising&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been three years since we first launched &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../ads-on-read-the-docs/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;ads on Read the Docs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
and while we gave a limited update in our &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../read-the-docs-2018-stats/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;2018 stats&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
we figured it was time to give an update on ethical advertising and how it is working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;advertising-without-tracking&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Advertising without tracking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our ethical advertising model is still going strong.&lt;/strong&gt;
We proved that it is possible to build a business model on top of advertising
without resorting to user tracking.
Unlike most other ad-supported sites, we show advertising based on the context of the page,
not by creating behavoral profiles of large numbers of individual users.
If you are browsing documentation for a Python project, you might see a relevant ad about Python.
It’s that simple and it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite a slow start to the year, we expect to earn about $75,000 from advertising in Q2.
This brings our advertising revenue back to the level
before our ads were &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../ads-and-adblocking/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;added to major ad blocking lists&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we do earn money from other sources such as our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.com&quot;&gt;commercial offering&lt;/a&gt;,
advertising continues to be our largest source of revenue and has allowed us
to expand our team to five full-time people.
Compared with three years ago when we were scraping along with very little money,
our community issue tracker and support requests receive prompt responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;progress&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Progress&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve made great progress on advertising over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We survived a major hit to revenue from ad blocking
without resorting to cat and mouse games of changing ad layouts and APIs to avoid ad blockers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/page/advertising/ethical-advertising.html#community-ads&quot;&gt;community ads program&lt;/a&gt; has been significantly expanded.
We are actively running free community advertising promoting over ten open source projects and conferences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While we never tracked users with advertising,
we put in place stricter &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../do-not-track/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;Do Not Track&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; privacy protections.
We continue to believe that advertising can be well targeted without tracking users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We launched an advertising vertical to let companies
&lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../lessons-from-hiring-manager-interviews/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;promote their open jobs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our advertising revenue share program tripled in size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ethical advertising approach, with no user tracking, has been key to our sustainability
and has allowed Read the Docs to continue to build new features and give back to our community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;what-s-next&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What’s next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have some really interesting developments coming regarding ethical advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking to add a few more projects to our ad &lt;strong&gt;revenue share program&lt;/strong&gt;
and help more projects reach sustainability with an ethical advertising approach.
If your project on Read the Docs does 100k+ pageviews per month
and you are interested in exploring a new revenue stream, please &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:ads&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;readthedocs&amp;#46;org?subject=Ethical%20Ads%20revenue%20share&quot;&gt;let us know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are testing a &lt;strong&gt;new text-only ad format&lt;/strong&gt; which we will detail in a future post.
Text-only ads are something we’ve wanted for a while because we believe they are less intrusive to readers
but easy for advertisers to experiment with multiple variations.
So far the results have been very promising and we are planning to roll this out more widely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;strong&gt;ethical ad network&lt;/strong&gt; is getting closer to launch.
It’s a shame, but there’s a critical lack of funding for open source projects
that form the building blocks of some extremely valuable software.
We believe that advertising can fill some of that gap
and Read the Docs can help by sharing some of the lessons we’ve learned building our own advertising.
If you know a site that might be interested in being a beta tester
of a pro-privacy ad network built specifically to help fund open source,
please &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:ads&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;readthedocs&amp;#46;org?subject=Ethical%20Ad%20Network%20beta&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisers always have a choice where to direct their marketing spend
and for many of them it would have been simpler to just go with the usual behemoth advertising platforms
rather than advertising with a niche site like Read the Docs.
I want to thank all our advertisers who believe in our approach and continue to support us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;admonition-would-your-company-like-to-reach-a-100-developer-audience admonition&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;first admonition-title&quot;&gt;Would your company like to reach a 100% developer audience?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;last&quot;&gt;Over 7 million developers Read the Docs each month. &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.org/sustainability/advertising/?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=readthedocs-blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=ethical-advertising-2019&quot;&gt;Get in front of them today&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/san-diego-ca/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Tips for Getting a Developer Interview</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/tips-for-getting-a-developer-interview/</id>
    <updated>2019-02-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-02-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/tips-for-getting-a-developer-interview/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;tips-for-getting-a-developer-interview&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last month, the Read the Docs team conducted 30-40 customer development interviews
with hiring managers and recruiters
at companies ranging from 5-person companies to the biggest names in tech.
We wanted to learn more about hiring processes at various companies
with the ultimate goal of building &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.org/sustainability/advertising/recruiting/?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=readthedocs-blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=next-developer-job&quot;&gt;a product to help companies find developers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time, we covered some &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../lessons-from-hiring-manager-interviews/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;tips for hiring managers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
based on what companies told us they were doing.
This time, we put together &lt;strong&gt;tips for candidates looking for their next job&lt;/strong&gt;
based on insights we heard from hiring managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than covering how to crack developer interviews
or how to gain the necessary technical skills,
these tips will focus on getting your foot in the door. Specifically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making your application stand out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving your application response rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting to the interview process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;when-applying-go-deep-not-wide&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When applying, go deep not wide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;“I don’t want candidates who drive by job sites and pepper every job they find”&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a candidate, there is a temptation to play the numbers game and apply to as many jobs as possible.
Many jobs sites make it easy to apply to many jobs quickly and this gives you that feeling that your job search is progressing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Based on what hiring managers told us, playing the numbers game isn’t the best approach.&lt;/strong&gt;
While it is a bit of a job-seekers market, especially for more senior talent,
companies are looking people who want to work for their company and who believe in their mission.
Hiring managers told us they want applicants who
“think about the company, then check for opportunities”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure align-default&quot; id=&quot;id1&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;A Facebook job post on LinkedIn with almost 300 applications in 2 weeks&quot; src=&quot;img/2019-facebook-job-opening.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;That’s almost 300 applications in 2 weeks on just one of the job sites where this is posted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;spend-a-little-more-time-on-your-application&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spend a little more time on your application&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it takes longer to apply to a job post
that requires a cover letter or requires answers to a few questions,
those are great ways to have your application stand out relative to other applicants.
You don’t want your resume to get lost in a stack of hundreds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we mentioned &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../lessons-from-hiring-manager-interviews/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;last time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
quite a few hiring managers we talked to started requiring a cover letter
or even just a couple questions that are unique to the company
in order to make their job filtering candidates easier
and get candidates who want to work there not those who just want a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the companies we talked to said when they post a job they got tons of applicants,
but that high quality, qualified applicants were still in short supply.
When 200 people apply to a job but only 20 are willing to do a cover letter,
a hiring manager can spend a lot more time per candidate with the smaller pool.
One hiring manager told us explicitly “fewer resumes is better because there’s less noise”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I know I said getting a developer job isn’t a numbers game,
this doesn’t strictly mean you can use these techniques
to apply to 2-3 jobs and you’ll get hired.
Sometimes by the time you apply, somebody is already in the final stages of getting hired.
The position may not &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; be open anymore.
Don’t get discouraged in your job search.
&lt;strong&gt;Finding the right match can take time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure align-default&quot; id=&quot;id2&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Questions from the DuckDuckGo application process&quot; src=&quot;img/2019-duckduckgo-application-questions.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Here’s some of the questions from the DuckDuckGo application process.
This is your place to stand out!
DuckDuckGo was &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; one of the companies we interviewed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;make-yourself-a-referral-use-your-network&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Make yourself a referral: use your network&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiring managers universally told us their top recruiting channel
is referrals from existing employees.
As a candidate, use this knowledge to your advantage and
&lt;strong&gt;make yourself into a referral hire&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did you see an acquaintance on social media post about job openings at their company?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does a friend or a friend of friend work at the company?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you have a first connection (or a very good 2nd connection) on LinkedIn who works there?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all of these cases, you should contact that person before applying.
Even if the person you know isn’t on the hiring team,
your contact might be able to put you in touch with the right person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;“Most [senior] people go through their network”&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a mid-level to senior candidate with 7+ years of experience,
this is even more important based on our interviews. At that stage of your career,
&lt;strong&gt;hiring managers we talked to expect a high quality candidate to do due diligence&lt;/strong&gt;
on the company and team to make sure it’s a mutual fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the exact route you take here,
getting in touch with the right people to learn more about the team,
the tech stack, and the company makes it clear that you’re very interested.
You’re far more likely to get a response, move on to the interview process,
and ultimately get hired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;establishing-contact-with-companies&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Establishing contact with companies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning yourself into a referral is easier for a senior candidate.
But what if this is your first or second job or don’t know anybody at the company?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After referral candidates, &lt;strong&gt;the next best hiring channel in our interviews
was local meetups and engaging the local community&lt;/strong&gt;.
Both startups and established companies – especially when they are actively hiring –
use meetups to find talent.
If you’re able to meet the hiring manager in person or establish some sort of connection,
in my experience, this raises your chances significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our interviews, another channel that mid-size and larger companies
we talked to used to recruit was to rely on their presense at conferences.
For many companies,
recruiting was the primary motivator to sponsor a conference and have a booth.
As a candidate, talking to the engineers at the booth and showing interest
can ensure that your application doesn’t get lost among all the applicants they get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a smaller company, it’s frequently possible to figure out exactly
who the hiring manager is from some combination of the website,
hiring posts, and LinkedIn. This is a great way to make a valuable connection
and make sure the role is a good fit.
Contacting the hiring manager cold requires a bit of finesse so make sure to be respectful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Places like the monthly HackerNews Who’s Hiring thread are fantastic
because they allow direct interaction with the hiring manager
and many companies list a person’s direct email to inquire about a position,
learn more directly from the source, and show you’re interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure align-default&quot; id=&quot;id3&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Some of the phrases heard from hiring managers in our interviews&quot; src=&quot;img/2019-hiring-manager-phrases.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;Here’s some of the phrases we heard from hiring managers in interviews.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By spending a bit more time on your application,
establishing contact with the company, and asking good questions about the work and team,
you are showing your intent and interest in the company.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to make sure the hiring manager or recruiter understands
that you’re a serious candidate and you want to work there on their team.
Using these methods will improve your response rate and &lt;strong&gt;help you get the interview&lt;/strong&gt;.
By doing a one-click apply on a job site, this is completely lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, I’d like to thank all the hiring managers who took the time to talk to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/san-diego-ca/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Lessons From and For Hiring Managers</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/lessons-from-hiring-manager-interviews/</id>
    <updated>2019-01-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2019-01-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/lessons-from-hiring-manager-interviews/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;lessons-from-and-for-hiring-managers&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last four weeks, the Read the Docs team did dozens of customer development interviews with engineering hiring managers.
We wanted to learn more about hiring processes at various companies
with the ultimate goal of building a product to help companies find developers.
We talked to people looking for talent at five person companies all the way up to the biggest names in tech.
In this post, I am going to cover some of the common things we heard from hiring managers
and &lt;strong&gt;share some ways for hiring managers to improve their company’s process&lt;/strong&gt;.
In our &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../tips-for-getting-a-developer-interview/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;next post in this series&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I will have some actionable tips
for job seekers based on the same interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this is a long post, I figured I’d share some of the key takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a strategy for getting more referrals&lt;/strong&gt; whether that is actively asking employees or having an overly generous referral bonus.
Referrals are probably your top source of candidates so figuring out how to get more will save you time and money in the end.
Then do the same for your other best recruiting channels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reach passive candidates&lt;/strong&gt;. There are a lot more passive candidates than active ones so have a plan to reach them.
Great developers (especially senior ones) probably aren’t actively looking for a new job and it’s a job-seekers market.
Even if somebody isn’t considering a new job at all, the next time they do, you want them to think of your company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recruiting for diversity is a focus&lt;/strong&gt; for hiring managers.
Put together a concrete plan for getting more diverse candidates and meeting your diversity goals.
Engaging with local developer communities and nonprofits and encouraging referrals worked well for companies we talked to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get more signal in your application process&lt;/strong&gt; by adding a step such as a cover letter, quiz,
or simply add a couple questions folks have to answer.
Making candidates spend even one extra minute on their application can save you hours filtering resumes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;why-is-read-the-docs-tackling-hiring-hasn-t-that-been-done&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why is Read the Docs tackling hiring? Hasn’t that been done?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we didn’t initially think about Read the Docs ads for recruiting,
based on some &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../hiring-developers-with-readthedocs/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;unexpected past successes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
we decided to position promoted jobs as one of our main verticals within our advertising.
Rather than dash forward and create a product, however, we started by just talking to hiring managers
to understand the hiring process better so we can best meet their needs with something we create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the questions we asked in our interviews was how long it took to hire their most recent developer?
Specifically, we asked hiring managers to consider how much time they and their team spent sourcing candidates,
filtering resumes, preparing for and doing phone and onsite interviews, and anything else.
Internal recruiters’ time is valuable too, but we figured the hiring manager
would probably underestimate how much time the recruiter spent since they didn’t directly observe it.
While answers were all over the place, the range with the most overlap was &lt;strong&gt;50-100 hours of engineering time to make a hire&lt;/strong&gt;.
No huge revelation here, but companies make a massive investment in hiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my days being an interviewer at Qualcomm and Amazon as well as a smaller startup,
I’d say fifty hours is on the low side for big company but about right for a smaller company.
When something costs 50+ engineering hours to do,
any improvement is worth a lot of time and money
and at Read the Docs we believe we can help significantly here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;top-hiring-channels&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Top hiring channels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was no big surprise to hear that &lt;strong&gt;referrals were the top hiring channel&lt;/strong&gt;.
The second best channel was a bit of a surprise with local meetups and local communities being very high in a majority of interviews
although this was less true among the largest companies we talked to.
Companies also had some success with recruiting at conferences, using various job sites, and proactive outreach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiring managers shared strategies with us that they used to increase the number of referral and community candidates they got.
Two different companies we talked to hosted multiple local meetups at their offices and one of those hiring managers said
“being plugged into the community” was their main channel for hiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another hiring manager who focused a lot on developers with security experience talked about having “LinkedIn parties”
where either a hiring manager or internal recruiter sat with engineers on their team one-on-one to go through their LinkedIn network.
Even when he heard a person “is great, but they’ll never change jobs”, that was a good candidate to target.
Security is such a high demand field, he said, that very few great people are actively looking for a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure align-default&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Job seeker timeline&quot; src=&quot;img/2019-job-seeker-timeline.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;reaching-people-who-aren-t-looking-is-critical&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reaching people who aren’t looking is critical&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of our biggest takeaways from the interviews was that companies wanted to reach candidates before they started actively looking.
Most of the hiring managers we talked to stressed the importance of getting in front of passive candidates.
Certainly fewer people are actively looking for developer jobs than those who are just open to a change.
A few different reasons were given but I actually think &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/magazine/20070501/column-guest.html&quot;&gt;Joel Spolsky had it right&lt;/a&gt; when he said
top developers “barely ever apply for jobs at all. That’s because they already have jobs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quote isn’t necessarily a slight against people who apply actively to jobs.
Virtually everyone I know in tech started their career applying to a job.
Rather, the message here is that as a developer becomes a mid-level developer
and then becomes a senior developer, they are more likely to rely on their network
to somewhat passively job seek rather than going through the front door
and simply applying on a company website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reaching people who aren’t actively looking is one area where Read the Docs can really help.
Companies want to reach them when they are just thinking about a new job or perhaps passively seeking.
Developers who come to our site are actively building software, not job-seeking.
Many of them are content at their current position.
For those that aren’t, this is a perfect place to showcase great companies
and help Read the Docs’ visitors to find their next job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;recruiters-can-be-worth-it&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recruiters can be worth it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each interview, we asked whether the company used recruiters or recruiting related services (eg. Hired, Triplebyte).
Universally, hiring managers brought up how expensive recruiters are,
but most of the people we talked to who had actually used recruiters in the past had a positive impression overall.
Hiring takes a ton of time, typically from senior folks at the company.
At smaller startups, that’s frequently the CEO or CTO.
Even though the price is high, recruiters who help speed that process along are worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the quote that really summed it up was from a VP of engineering at a startup that just raised a Series B.
He’s trying to grow his team by 10 developers this year (about a 50% increase).
His experience hiring his first couple developers through a 2-person boutique recruiting firm was great and
he would use them for hiring everyone “if hiring 10 people didn’t mean $100k+” in fees alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure: &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://triplebyte.com&quot;&gt;Triplebyte&lt;/a&gt; is an advertiser on Read the Docs. We’re fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;diversity-and-inclusivity-in-hiring&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Diversity and inclusivity in hiring&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn’t ask any questions around hiring for diversity
but fully six hiring managers volunteered information on their companies’ strategies
for getting more diverse candidates.
This is why I love this kind of interview where the goal is just to listen to what hiring managers say
and dig deeper when you hear something interesting.
Some of the larger companies we talked to had explicit diversity goals set at the company level.
Even among the hiring managers at smaller companies,
they shared some tactics they used to get more diverse candidates to apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the companies with hard diversity goals, most of them told us that their strategy
entailed syndicating their job openings to diversity focused jobs sites
or in some cases engaging directly with relevant interest groups.
In terms of efficacy, reviews of these various jobs boards was mixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the more positive side, hiring managers cited
Girl Develop It, Black Girls Code, and PyLadies as fantastic channels
for &lt;strong&gt;both increasing candidate diversity and for high quality applicants&lt;/strong&gt;.
Two companies also talked about trying to decrease bias
in their job postings using &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://textio.com/&quot;&gt;Textio&lt;/a&gt; and similar services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having multiple people mention diversity completely unprompted really shows that this topic
is becoming higher priority for companies and hiring managers.
It also shows that it if hiring for diversity is important to your company,
you need to have a plan for actually making those goals a reality.
It’s worth checking whether the strategy actually works too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;remember-sourcing-is-the-bigger-problem&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Remember, sourcing is the bigger problem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every single hiring manager we talked to complained about the time they spent filtering resumes from applicants.
Some choice quotes I heard included “95% of applicants weren’t a fit” even after only reviewing the resume
and a hiring manager who posted to a very popular remote-only job board told me he got “literally one thousand applications”.
While I believe this is a legitimate complaint,
I think &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://blog.alinelerner.com/building-a-product-in-the-technical-recruiting-space-read-this-first/&quot;&gt;Aline Lerner, founder of interviewing.io said it best&lt;/a&gt;
when she said “Engineering hiring isn’t a filtering problem. It’s a sourcing problem.”
The reason we heard it a lot is that filtering is a very time-consuming task that hiring managers directly deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real problem here is that &lt;strong&gt;the number of applicants to a job post is a vanity metric&lt;/strong&gt;.
What hiring managers are looking for is qualified applicants, which is harder to gauge without some additional work.
One of the problems here is that a lot of jobs sites make it really easy for candidates to apply to lots of jobs.
This is understandable from their perspective as more applicants makes their platform seem more valuable.
There’s no reason for a job board to put artificial barriers into the application funnel,
but hiring managers told us they want candidates who want to work for their company
not somebody who is applying to every job out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of building product here, I think hiring managers just need a few tweaks
to get more of a signal of candidate quality and intent in their applications.
A few of the hiring managers we talked to described how they did this.
Multiple hiring managers mentioned how they required a cover letter that answered specific questions (“why us” was the most popular).
Another hiring manager described how his hiring system just asked a few short questions of candidates
– for example, “what is the software project you’re most proud of” – when they applied.
When a candidate didn’t do a cover letter or didn’t answer the questions, they weren’t considered.
The latter solution seemed like the best of both worlds as it solves the one-click apply problem without being too much of a barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to thank all the hiring managers who took time out of their days (or in some cases evenings) to talk to us.
If you’re a hiring manager or an internal company recruiter and you’d like to share your experiences and help Read the Docs,
please &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:ads&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;readthedocs&amp;#46;org?subject=Lessons+From+Hiring+Managers+Post&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check back soon for our &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../tips-for-getting-a-developer-interview/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;next post in this series&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
which covers tips for candidates based on the same interviews!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; This blog was updated to mention our &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../tips-for-getting-a-developer-interview/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;new post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the series&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;admonition-ready-to-hire-your-next-developer-fast admonition&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;first admonition-title&quot;&gt;Ready to hire your next developer, fast!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;last&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.org/sustainability/advertising/recruiting/?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=readthedocs-blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=hiring-manager-interviews-i&quot;&gt;Get in front of passive candidates already using your tech&lt;/a&gt; by promoting your job openings with Read the Docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/san-diego-ca/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Tips to Hire Developers with Read the Docs</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/hiring-developers-with-readthedocs/</id>
    <updated>2018-10-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-10-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/hiring-developers-with-readthedocs/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;tips-to-hire-developers-with-read-the-docs&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the Docs is probably not the first place you think of if you are recruiting.
However, over &lt;strong&gt;7 million unique developers use Read the Docs each month&lt;/strong&gt; from all over the world.
We didn’t set out to build a better job board,
but after a number of advertisers used our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/advertising/ethical-advertising.html&quot;&gt;ethical ads&lt;/a&gt; for recruiting,
we discovered that Read the Docs was a great place to find developer talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;hiring-with-read-the-docs-works&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hiring with Read the Docs works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers are not always actively job seeking
by browsing job boards or company careers pages.
However, they are on Read the Docs reading about the libraries and frameworks they use.
Even when people aren’t actively looking for a new job,
many are open to exploring new opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Read the Docs, we found that developers engage with hiring ads
at a higher rate than any other kind of advertising.
With hiring ads, developers get ads that are relevant and interesting
and companies reach the folks actively using the tech they are recruiting for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure align-default&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Click-through rate by ad type Q3 2018&quot; src=&quot;img/2018-ctr-adtype.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;be-specific-and-find-the-right-developers&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Be specific and find the right developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for Python developers,
you can configure your hiring ad to only show on Python related documentation.
You can further refine your audience to Read the Docs visitors in specific regions.
Whether you are looking for a remote Python data scientist or a blockchain developer in Switzerland,
be as specific as possible.
This ensures you don’t get unqualified candidates
as well as making sure you catch the eyes of the people you are interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;set-the-right-expectations&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Set the right expectations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any type of advertising, setting appropriate expectations can make the difference
between a lackluster and successful campaign. In hiring, it is even more critical.
This means making sure that your hiring ad for a front-end JavaScript developer
links directly to your JavaScript developer job listing page where people can click “apply”.
Don’t link to a listing of all of your open positions unless your hiring ad sets that expectation.
Nothing is worse for the developer than clicking on a hiring ad
and not knowing what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, some things can set the wrong kind of expectation.
Most developers have seen enough hiring posts for “rockstars” and “ninjas” to know what to expect.
Be honest and upfront and you will attract the right folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;stand-out&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stand out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers get contacted all the time by recruiters
and it can be difficult to show prospective employees why they should check out your company.
People look for all sorts of different things when seeking a new job
from working with a high-caliber team to working for a company whose goals they agree with.
You should highlight your best selling points right on your hiring ad as early as possible.
If your company affords a fantastic work/life balance, mention that.
A company in a great location, with a beautiful office, and top of the line hardware
should definitely feature that.
Focusing on your best attributes shows you care about your developers
and helps you appeal to people who care about your products and mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;admonition-are-you-hiring admonition&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;first admonition-title&quot;&gt;Are you hiring?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;last&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.org/sustainability/advertising/recruiting/?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=readthedocs-blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=hire-developers&quot;&gt;Find qualified candidates&lt;/a&gt; already using your tech by promoting your job openings with Read the Docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/san-diego-ca/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Community Advertising</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/community-ads-2018/</id>
    <updated>2018-09-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-09-06T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/community-ads-2018/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;community-advertising&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/advertising/ethical-advertising.html&quot;&gt;ethical advertising&lt;/a&gt; model,
Read the Docs &lt;strong&gt;gives away&lt;/strong&gt; 10% of our ad inventory
to projects, conferences, and other initiatives in the open source community.
Many of these projects operate as Read the Docs did in the past with little to no income.
These are not groups that traditionally have the resources to use paid advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have run ads for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various Python conferences from &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://us.pycon.org/&quot;&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; to smaller regional conferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many topic or framework specific conferences such as &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://djangocon.us/&quot;&gt;Djangocon US&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainoss.org/&quot;&gt;Sustain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/psf/&quot;&gt;Python Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/&quot;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pybee.org/&quot;&gt;Beeware&lt;/a&gt; - tools and libraries for building native apps in Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/godotengine&quot;&gt;Godot&lt;/a&gt; - an open source game engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://kiwitcms.org/&quot;&gt;Kiwi TCMS&lt;/a&gt; - an open source test case management system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://worldpossible.org/&quot;&gt;World Possible&lt;/a&gt; - an education non-profit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.writethedocs.org/&quot;&gt;Write the Docs&lt;/a&gt; - a series of events for documentatarians&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;get-in-touch-we-can-help&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Get in touch. We can help!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you run a conference, non-profit, or a funding strapped open source project,
we would love to help you get the word out.
Make sure you qualify for our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/advertising/ethical-advertising.html#community-ads&quot;&gt;community ads&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:ads&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;readthedocs&amp;#46;org&quot;&gt;send us an email&lt;/a&gt;
to be considered for the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any feedback about our community advertising program,
we’d love to hear from you too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/san-diego-ca/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">HTTPS for Custom Domains</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/https-for-custom-domains/</id>
    <updated>2018-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/https-for-custom-domains/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;https-for-custom-domains&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the Docs hosts documentation for over 80,000 open source projects
and over 2,500 of those projects are hosted on their own individual domains.
Documentation hosted on &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;*.readthedocs.io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; has supported HTTPS for a number of years,
but one of our most requested features was to make HTTPS on other domains easy.
Today we are happy to announce that &lt;strong&gt;Read the Docs supports HTTPS on custom domains&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Cloudflare contacted us to support HTTPS
for the thousands of open source documentation projects on their own domains.
They generously provided us with their &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/ssl-for-saas-providers/&quot;&gt;SSL for SaaS&lt;/a&gt; package
to ease the integration on our side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;why-https-is-important&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why HTTPS is important&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HTTPS encrypts traffic between your computer and Read the Docs’ servers
and allows your browser to verify that the website you are talking to
is the one that you requested.
HTTPS ensures there is no man-in-the-middle snooping on your connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;configuring-your-domain&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Configuring your domain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you followed our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/alternate_domains.html&quot;&gt;documentation for custom domains&lt;/a&gt;
and you are using a &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;CNAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; to point to Read the Docs,
no action is required on your part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have had your Read the Docs setup for many years you may have followed some old directions
that suggested creating a &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;CNAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;readthedocs.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;slug&amp;gt;.readthedocs.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.
Depending on your setup, we may not have been able to issue a certificate for your domain.
In that case, update your &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;CNAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; to point to &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;readthedocs.io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;why-did-it-take-so-long&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why did it take so long?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s 2018! HTTPS is supposed to be easy, right?
For a few domains, getting a certificate isn’t too hard.
For 2,500+ domains, things get a bit more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We identified a number of challenges including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrying failed requests to issue certificates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handling when users remove DNS records that would allow us to issue certificates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting our web servers and load balancers to handle dynamically adding and updating certificates on the fly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handling recurring tasks to re-issue updated certificates before they expire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare reduced most of this complexity to a few API calls made when a new domain is configured or removed.
Without their support, we would still be working on this feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few more things left on our road map for this feature.
In the next few weeks we will begin to generate HTTPS links for custom domains where we have a certificate.
After that change has been deployed for a few weeks, we will begin to redirect custom domain traffic to HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, if you’re having any trouble with a particular domain,
don’t hesitate to let us know in our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues&quot;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
