<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">Read the Docs Blog - Posts tagged release</title>
  <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/release/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com" />
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/release/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <generator uri="http://ablog.readthedocs.org" version="0.9.5">ABlog</generator>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/release/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Theme release 1.0.0rc1</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/theme-release-100rc1/</id>
    <updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-08-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/theme-release-100rc1/" />
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;theme-release-1-0-0rc1&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;admonition-update-version-1-0-0-has-been-released admonition&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;first admonition-title&quot;&gt;Update: Version 1.0.0 has been released!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1.0.0 version of sphinx_rtd_theme was released Sept 13, 2021. You can
install the latest version with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight-console notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;pip install &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;sphinx-rtd-theme~=1.0.0&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can upgrade the version installed using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;last highlight-console notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;gp&quot;&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;pip install --upgrade sphinx-rtd-theme
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are closing in on the next official release of &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/readthedocs/sphinx_rtd_theme&quot;&gt;sphinx_rtd_theme&lt;/a&gt;, and
we’re happy to announce that release candidate version 1.0.0rc1 was
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/sphinx-rtd-theme/1.0.0rc1/&quot;&gt;released to PyPI&lt;/a&gt; last week! Project maintainers can contribute to the final
release by &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;#testing&quot;&gt;testing the release candidate&lt;/a&gt; and raising any potential
bugs on &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/readthedocs/sphinx_rtd_theme/issues&quot;&gt;our issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version 1.0.0 adds support for &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/Sphinx/&quot;&gt;Sphinx&lt;/a&gt; 4, fixes several issues stemming
from &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/docutils/&quot;&gt;docutils&lt;/a&gt; 0.17, and contains several backwards-incompatible changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;backwards-incompatible-changes&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Backwards incompatible changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users need to be aware of several backwards incompatible changes before
upgrading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Support dropped for old dependencies&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Support is removed for Sphinx versions 1.6 or older, and for Python versions
3.0 to 3.3. Theme developers no longer test using these versions and
compatibility is not guaranteed for these versions.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;HTML4 support will be removed&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Support for the Sphinx HTML4 writer will be deprecated in release 2.0. A
deprecation warning was added to alert users still using the HTML4 writer.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Installation from source will be deprecated soon&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Tentatively scheduled for release 3.0, installation from source will no
longer be a supported installation method. Currently, users are installing
directly from our GitHub repository, which complicates development of static
assets. A deprecation warning was added to alert users of the upcoming
change.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;highlights&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the most significant additions included in release 1.0.0:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Support for new dependencies&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;The theme now supports Sphinx 4 and docutils 0.17, both the latest in each
respective release series.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;New accessibility features&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Also added were a number of accessibility updates, including better keyboard
navigation support and more descriptive navigation for screen readers.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Added 4 new translations&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;The theme is close to being almost fully translated in 14 different
languages. This will provide project maintainers with localized navigation
elements and accessibility content.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://sphinx-rtd-theme.readthedocs.io/en/latest/development.html#roadmap&quot;&gt;The theme roadmap&lt;/a&gt; has more information on upcoming releases, and
backwards incompatible changes for each. A full list of changes included in this
release is available in &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://sphinx-rtd-theme.readthedocs.io/en/latest/changelog.html&quot;&gt;the theme changelog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;testing&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1.0.0rc1 release is a pre-release package, meaning it will not install by
default as the most recent release. Project maintainers will need to specify the
release version explicitly to install the release candidate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your package’s &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;extra_requirements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, or a separate &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;requirements.txt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
file, you can pin this dependency with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight-default notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;sphinx_rtd_theme&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;~=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mf&quot;&gt;1.0.0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;rc1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you notice any new, unwanted behavior, feel free to open an issue
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/readthedocs/sphinx_rtd_theme/issues&quot;&gt;on our issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;upcoming-changes&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Upcoming changes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have several upcoming releases planned, covered in more depth in
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://sphinx-rtd-theme.readthedocs.io/en/latest/development.html#roadmap&quot;&gt;the theme roadmap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next official release, currently targeted for October or November, will be
version 1.1. This release will contain additional bug fixes and will be the last
release supporting Sphinx versions less than 3.0. The next planed release will
be version 2.0, in early 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2.0 release will be dropping support for a number of old dependencies,
including Sphinx versions &amp;lt; 3.0, Sphinx HTML4 writer support, and Internet
Explorer 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the theme moves away from supporting direct installation through our GitHub
repository, we want to preserve development previews of theme releases. In
addition to several more focused releases on the theme roadmap, we will also be
periodically publishing development releases to PyPI. This will be the
prescribed method to use unreleased theme changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thanks!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to contributor &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/Blendify&quot;&gt;Blendify&lt;/a&gt; for keeping up with support for fresh
dependencies, and new contributor &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/nienn&quot;&gt;nienn&lt;/a&gt; for helping with bug fixes and the
heavy amount of testing required for this release!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/release/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Release for May 12, 2017</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/release-2017-05-12/</id>
    <updated>2017-05-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2017-05-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/release-2017-05-12/" />
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;release-for-may-12-2017&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, we rolled out improved webhook management for projects, and several
bug fixes around our upgrade to Sphinx 1.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;webhook-management&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Webhook management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been slowly making upgrades to our webhook management page. Projects that
set up new webhooks will see a list of webhooks that we have configured,
including HTTP exchanges that we encounter from each remote webhook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the other improvements to our webhook management include a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/webhooks.html#using-the-generic-api-integration&quot;&gt;new generic
webhook endpoint&lt;/a&gt;, the ability to create arbitrary webhooks,
and the ability to now re-establish webhooks on a per-provider basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can play with the new features by selecting a project, opening the project
admin dashboard, and selecting &lt;strong&gt;Integrations&lt;/strong&gt;. If your project is relatively
new, webhook integrations will be created for existing remote webhooks. If your
project has been configured for a long time, or you are using our old webhook
endpoints, such as &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;http://readthedocs.org/github&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;, you won’t notice anything
new on the integrations dashboard page. You can still manually create a webhook
and configure your repository to point to the new Read the Docs webhook
endpoint however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;bug-fixes&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the release of Sphinx 1.5, we set this version as the default version
for Sphinx projects on Read the Docs. This in turn caused an issue with our
override of the Sphinx search mechanism. We currently override this to provide
our own search indexes, however the patch to this file was incompatible with
Sphinx 1.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to this incompatibility, if a search query did not return anything from our
indexes, but did match the Sphinx internal index, the links would have been
incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are now patching this search mechanism regardless of which version of Sphinx
is used, and the broken links are no longer returned in the search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;problems&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Problems?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any problems with any of the recent changes, feel free to open
up a bug report on our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues/&quot;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
