<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">Read the Docs Blog - Posts from Bend, Oregon</title>
  <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/bend-oregon/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2021-02-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com" />
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/bend-oregon/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <generator uri="http://ablog.readthedocs.org" version="0.9.5">ABlog</generator>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/bend-oregon/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Read the Docs Community downtime due to migrations to AWS</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/aws-migration/</id>
    <updated>2021-02-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-02-05T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/aws-migration/" />
    <author>
      <name>Eric Holscher</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;read-the-docs-community-downtime-due-to-migrations-to-aws&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: The migration was successful and the site has been fully restored as of 4PM PST.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to make you aware that on Friday, February 12th at 1pm PST (4pm EST, 21:00 UTC),
Read the Docs Community (readthedocs.org) will be having a &lt;strong&gt;scheduled dashboard downtime of approximately 4 hours&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure minimal impact for our users,
we are performing this upgrade during a Friday afternoon
which is one of our lowest usage periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this maintenance window, &lt;strong&gt;documentation will continue to be online&lt;/strong&gt;
but new documentation builds will not trigger and the Read the Docs dashboard will be unavailable.
New builds and webhooks will begin processing once the maintenance is over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are moving our service to our new home on Amazon Web Services
who have generously provided us with credits to support open source software.
This is the same platform which Read the Docs for Business is hosted,
which will allow us to reuse a lot of the same code between the sites.
This should simplify our operations considerably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank Microsoft Azure for sponsoring our hosting for the past 2.5 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your understanding of this maintenance downtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/bend-oregon/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Pull Request Builders available for all users</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/pull-request-builder-general-availability/</id>
    <updated>2021-01-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-01-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/pull-request-builder-general-availability/" />
    <author>
      <name>Eric Holscher</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;pull-request-builders-available-for-all-users&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce that &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/guides/autobuild-docs-for-pull-requests.html&quot;&gt;Pull Request building&lt;/a&gt; is now available for all Read the Docs users.
We have been working on this feature for over a year,
and having it available for all our users is a major milestone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feature allows users to confirm documentation builds correctly for all of their commits,
not just ones merged into branches that are activated on Read the Docs.
This moves documentation into your continuous integration pipeline,
and improves the workflow for everyone working on documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure align-default&quot; id=&quot;id1&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;GitHub Build Status Reporting for Pull Requests.&quot; src=&quot;img/github-build-status-reporting.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 70%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption-text&quot;&gt;GitHub Build Status Reporting for Pull Requests&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about this new feature in our &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../building-docs-for-pull-requests/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;previous blog post announcing it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and in our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/page/guides/autobuild-docs-for-pull-requests.html&quot;&gt;documentation for the feature&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;serving-docs-for-every-branch&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Serving docs for every branch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with building and validating each branch on your repository,
&lt;strong&gt;we also host a rendered version of the documentation.&lt;/strong&gt;
This allows you to see exactly how the docs will look when they are deployed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building the documentation on Read the Docs during the development process also helps test integration with Read the Docs.
The entire build process is run for each commit,
so this will ensure that builds work as expected when you’re ready to merge into production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These previews will stay live for 90 days from the time you merge or close the Pull Request,
allowing you to finish any outstanding work on the task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;limitations&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the increased demand for build resources,
the Pull Request builders have the following limitations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the Docs search is not enabled on these versions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only HTML versions of the documentation are built (not PDF, ePub, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation builds are concurrency limited. Read the Docs for Business concurrency varies based on your plan, and Read the Docs Community are limited to 2 concurrent builds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working to address these limitations over time,
but given the increase in scale with these builds it will take some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;give-us-feedback&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Give us feedback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We always love to hear from our users about the product.
If you have feedback on this feature of any others,
you can always reach us at &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:hello&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;readthedocs&amp;#46;org&quot;&gt;hello&lt;span&gt;&amp;#64;&lt;/span&gt;readthedocs&lt;span&gt;&amp;#46;&lt;/span&gt;org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/bend-oregon/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Read the Docs for Business Maintenance Window - February 5</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/rtd-business-downtime-feb-5/</id>
    <updated>2021-01-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-01-25T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/rtd-business-downtime-feb-5/" />
    <author>
      <name>Eric Holscher</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;read-the-docs-for-business-maintenance-window-february-5&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: This maintenance window has concluded at 5:40 PM PST.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to make you aware that on Friday, February 5 at 5:00pm PST (8:00pm EST, Saturday 01:00 UTC),
Read the Docs for Business (readthedocs.com) will be having a &lt;strong&gt;scheduled downtime of approximately 2 hours&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this maintenance window, &lt;strong&gt;documentation will continue to be online&lt;/strong&gt; but new documentation builds will not trigger and the Read the Docs dashboard will be unavailable. New builds and webhooks will begin processing once the maintenance is over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure minimal impact for our users, we are performing this upgrade during a Friday afternoon which is one of our lowest usage periods. This maintenance window is for a required database version upgrade which we couldn’t perform in place. While these kinds of things do happen from time to time, we haven’t had a scheduled downtime on Read the Docs for Business in a few years. Doing this helps us ensure that our services perform well and have up-to-date security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your understanding of this maintenance downtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the Docs team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/location/bend-oregon/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Read the Docs is hiring for multiple positions</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/read-the-docs-is-hiring-q1-2021/</id>
    <updated>2021-01-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2021-01-06T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/read-the-docs-is-hiring-q1-2021/" />
    <author>
      <name>Eric Holscher</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;read-the-docs-is-hiring-for-multiple-positions&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the Docs received a &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../czi-grant-announcement/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;grant to support scientific software&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; at the beginning of this year.
As part of this,
we are hiring for two new positions related to the grant work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../job-frontend/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;frontend developer with design skills&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../../job-devrel/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;developer advocate with documentation skills&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;This position has been filled, and is no longer active&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please look at each of the job postings for much more detail on what to expect with the job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to be able to expand our small team and increase the support we’re giving to the scientific open source community.
Throughout 2021 we are going to be vastly improving our documentation and building major new features around embedding documentation content,
based on the work from this grant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;how-hiring-will-be-structured&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How hiring will be structured&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way we are currently planning to structure this work is to have 50% of the time spent working on grant work,
and the other 50% working on Read the Docs itself.
The codebase and community we’re building require a good amount of onboarding time,
so we are excited to be able to use the grant funds to also improve the overall experience of Read the Docs users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can apply to the jobs with the links above to the full job descriptions,
where you will be asked to fill out a form with a few questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;about-read-the-docs&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About Read the Docs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the Docs is a large open source project providing documentation building and hosting.
You can think of it a continuous integration for docs.
We do around 500 million pageviews each year.
We are a small team,
but &lt;strong&gt;this role will have a large impact of millions of users.&lt;/strong&gt;
Almost all of our codebase is open source
and we feel strongly about supporting the community while sustaining the project in an ethical manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
