<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">Read the Docs Blog - Posts tagged pycon</title>
  <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/pycon/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com" />
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/pycon/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <generator uri="http://ablog.readthedocs.org" version="0.9.5">ABlog</generator>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/tag/pycon/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">PyCon 2017 in Review</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/pycon-2017/</id>
    <updated>2017-05-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2017-05-31T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/pycon-2017/" />
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;pycon-2017-in-review&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are finally getting back to normal for us after another very busy PyCon.
It’s always wonderful seeing old friends and getting a chance to meet new
friends from the community. PyCon provides a great outlet to talk to others in
our community about the problems we all face as open source developers and open
source companies – like funding, sustainability, and building community. We are
sad to see PyCon leave Portland, but luckily &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://www.pycascades.com/&quot;&gt;PyCascades&lt;/a&gt; will soon be filling
the void left in &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cascadia_(bioregion)&quot;&gt;Cascadia&lt;/a&gt; after PyCon moves on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, we announced official sprints on Read the Docs during the sprint
week following PyCon. We focused our sprint efforts on code cleanup, in order
to avoid the problems on-boarding new contributors we normally face as a large
project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sprints went surprisingly well this year. We were able to enlist the help
of several new contributors during sprints, and folks didn’t waste any time
diving into the code. It was a large relief to finally spend some time
addressing code cleanup and removal. &lt;strong&gt;Contributors were able to create and
merge 38 pull requests over the week&lt;/strong&gt;, and we’re still wrapping up work on
several other pull requests. Our work focused on several areas in particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Linting strictness&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;When we started a serious effort to lint our codebase, we decided to address
linting incrementally. We currently do a primary pass with low strictness,
and a second pass of higher strictness only on select paths. During the
sprints, contributors were able to pick off and focus on a single Django
application. Cumulatively, contributors were able to fix linting issues
across all of our applications and we’re very close to again raising our
strictness application-wide.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Code removal&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Several contributors moved on to hunting down and removing some unused code
and dependencies. Having started with linting and testing problems, these
contributors seemed well primed to understanding more complex parts of our
code. We were able to remove several unused legacy pieces of code and some
unused dependencies as a result.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Python 3&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Contributor &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/gthank&quot;&gt;gthank&lt;/a&gt; started porting Read the Docs to Python 3 before the
sprints, and was able to drop by our sprint to debug some problems with
porting. We’ve been wanting to port to Python 3 for years now, but
unfortunately, we could never justify this work as the core team. This pull
request is still a work in progress, but we anxiously await being able to
make the switch to Python 3.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Read the Docs core team is small, we can’t easily justify using our time
to focus on long standing issues with code quality, so the PyCon sprints were a perfect
opportunity to focus on this type of clean up. Our codebase is complex and
unwieldy to new contributors, so focusing on linting and testing allowed
contributors to jump in without having to spend the better part of a day setting
up our full stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were very gracious to have all of this help. A big thanks once again to all
of our new contributors who stuck around and contributed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/cmc333333&quot;&gt;cmc333333&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/lordmauve&quot;&gt;lordmauve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/fmoor&quot;&gt;fmoor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/smcoll&quot;&gt;smcoll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/gthank&quot;&gt;gthank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PyCon has now wrapped up, but our next stop this summer is &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://2017.djangocon.us/&quot;&gt;DjangoCon 2017&lt;/a&gt; in
Spokane, WA. We look forward to seeing some more of you there and hopefully
working with some of you to sprint on Read the Docs again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
