<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">Read the Docs Blog - Posted in 2018</title>
  <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/2018/atom.xml</id>
  <updated>2018-10-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com" />
  <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/2018/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <generator uri="http://ablog.readthedocs.org" version="0.9.5">ABlog</generator>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/2018/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Tips to Hire Developers with Read the Docs</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/hiring-developers-with-readthedocs/</id>
    <updated>2018-10-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-10-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/hiring-developers-with-readthedocs/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;tips-to-hire-developers-with-read-the-docs&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the Docs is probably not the first place you think of if you are recruiting.
However, over &lt;strong&gt;7 million unique developers use Read the Docs each month&lt;/strong&gt; from all over the world.
We didn’t set out to build a better job board,
but after a number of advertisers used our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/advertising/ethical-advertising.html&quot;&gt;ethical ads&lt;/a&gt; for recruiting,
we discovered that Read the Docs was a great place to find developer talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;hiring-with-read-the-docs-works&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hiring with Read the Docs works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers are not always actively job seeking
by browsing job boards or company careers pages.
However, they are on Read the Docs reading about the libraries and frameworks they use.
Even when people aren’t actively looking for a new job,
many are open to exploring new opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Read the Docs, we found that developers engage with hiring ads
at a higher rate than any other kind of advertising.
With hiring ads, developers get ads that are relevant and interesting
and companies reach the folks actively using the tech they are recruiting for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure align-default&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Click-through rate by ad type Q3 2018&quot; src=&quot;img/2018-ctr-adtype.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;be-specific-and-find-the-right-developers&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Be specific and find the right developers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for Python developers,
you can configure your hiring ad to only show on Python related documentation.
You can further refine your audience to Read the Docs visitors in specific regions.
Whether you are looking for a remote Python data scientist or a blockchain developer in Switzerland,
be as specific as possible.
This ensures you don’t get unqualified candidates
as well as making sure you catch the eyes of the people you are interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;set-the-right-expectations&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Set the right expectations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any type of advertising, setting appropriate expectations can make the difference
between a lackluster and successful campaign. In hiring, it is even more critical.
This means making sure that your hiring ad for a front-end JavaScript developer
links directly to your JavaScript developer job listing page where people can click “apply”.
Don’t link to a listing of all of your open positions unless your hiring ad sets that expectation.
Nothing is worse for the developer than clicking on a hiring ad
and not knowing what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, some things can set the wrong kind of expectation.
Most developers have seen enough hiring posts for “rockstars” and “ninjas” to know what to expect.
Be honest and upfront and you will attract the right folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;stand-out&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stand out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers get contacted all the time by recruiters
and it can be difficult to show prospective employees why they should check out your company.
People look for all sorts of different things when seeking a new job
from working with a high-caliber team to working for a company whose goals they agree with.
You should highlight your best selling points right on your hiring ad as early as possible.
If your company affords a fantastic work/life balance, mention that.
A company in a great location, with a beautiful office, and top of the line hardware
should definitely feature that.
Focusing on your best attributes shows you care about your developers
and helps you appeal to people who care about your products and mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;admonition-are-you-hiring admonition&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;first admonition-title&quot;&gt;Are you hiring?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;last&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.org/sustainability/advertising/recruiting/?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=readthedocs-blog&amp;amp;utm_campaign=hire-developers&quot;&gt;Find qualified candidates&lt;/a&gt; already using your tech by promoting your job openings with Read the Docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/2018/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Community Advertising</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/community-ads-2018/</id>
    <updated>2018-09-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-09-06T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/community-ads-2018/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;community-advertising&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/advertising/ethical-advertising.html&quot;&gt;ethical advertising&lt;/a&gt; model,
Read the Docs &lt;strong&gt;gives away&lt;/strong&gt; 10% of our ad inventory
to projects, conferences, and other initiatives in the open source community.
Many of these projects operate as Read the Docs did in the past with little to no income.
These are not groups that traditionally have the resources to use paid advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have run ads for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various Python conferences from &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://us.pycon.org/&quot;&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; to smaller regional conferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many topic or framework specific conferences such as &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://djangocon.us/&quot;&gt;Djangocon US&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://sustainoss.org/&quot;&gt;Sustain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.python.org/psf/&quot;&gt;Python Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/&quot;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pybee.org/&quot;&gt;Beeware&lt;/a&gt; - tools and libraries for building native apps in Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/godotengine&quot;&gt;Godot&lt;/a&gt; - an open source game engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://kiwitcms.org/&quot;&gt;Kiwi TCMS&lt;/a&gt; - an open source test case management system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://worldpossible.org/&quot;&gt;World Possible&lt;/a&gt; - an education non-profit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.writethedocs.org/&quot;&gt;Write the Docs&lt;/a&gt; - a series of events for documentatarians&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;get-in-touch-we-can-help&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Get in touch. We can help!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you run a conference, non-profit, or a funding strapped open source project,
we would love to help you get the word out.
Make sure you qualify for our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/advertising/ethical-advertising.html#community-ads&quot;&gt;community ads&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:ads&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;readthedocs&amp;#46;org&quot;&gt;send us an email&lt;/a&gt;
to be considered for the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any feedback about our community advertising program,
we’d love to hear from you too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/2018/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">HTTPS for Custom Domains</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/https-for-custom-domains/</id>
    <updated>2018-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/https-for-custom-domains/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;https-for-custom-domains&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the Docs hosts documentation for over 80,000 open source projects
and over 2,500 of those projects are hosted on their own individual domains.
Documentation hosted on &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;*.readthedocs.io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; has supported HTTPS for a number of years,
but one of our most requested features was to make HTTPS on other domains easy.
Today we are happy to announce that &lt;strong&gt;Read the Docs supports HTTPS on custom domains&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Cloudflare contacted us to support HTTPS
for the thousands of open source documentation projects on their own domains.
They generously provided us with their &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cloudflare.com/ssl-for-saas-providers/&quot;&gt;SSL for SaaS&lt;/a&gt; package
to ease the integration on our side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;why-https-is-important&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why HTTPS is important&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HTTPS encrypts traffic between your computer and Read the Docs’ servers
and allows your browser to verify that the website you are talking to
is the one that you requested.
HTTPS ensures there is no man-in-the-middle snooping on your connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;configuring-your-domain&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Configuring your domain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you followed our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/alternate_domains.html&quot;&gt;documentation for custom domains&lt;/a&gt;
and you are using a &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;CNAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; to point to Read the Docs,
no action is required on your part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have had your Read the Docs setup for many years you may have followed some old directions
that suggested creating a &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;CNAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;readthedocs.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;slug&amp;gt;.readthedocs.org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.
Depending on your setup, we may not have been able to issue a certificate for your domain.
In that case, update your &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;CNAME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt; to point to &lt;code class=&quot;docutils literal notranslate&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pre&quot;&gt;readthedocs.io&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;why-did-it-take-so-long&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why did it take so long?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s 2018! HTTPS is supposed to be easy, right?
For a few domains, getting a certificate isn’t too hard.
For 2,500+ domains, things get a bit more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We identified a number of challenges including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retrying failed requests to issue certificates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handling when users remove DNS records that would allow us to issue certificates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting our web servers and load balancers to handle dynamically adding and updating certificates on the fly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handling recurring tasks to re-issue updated certificates before they expire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare reduced most of this complexity to a few API calls made when a new domain is configured or removed.
Without their support, we would still be working on this feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few more things left on our road map for this feature.
In the next few weeks we will begin to generate HTTPS links for custom domains where we have a certificate.
After that change has been deployed for a few weeks, we will begin to redirect custom domain traffic to HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, if you’re having any trouble with a particular domain,
don’t hesitate to let us know in our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues&quot;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/2018/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Planned Move to Azure</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/azure-migration/</id>
    <updated>2018-08-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-08-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/azure-migration/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;planned-move-to-azure&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to make you aware that on Saturday August 18 at 10:00am PDT (1:00pm EDT, 17:00 UTC),
Read the Docs will be having a &lt;strong&gt;scheduled downtime of approximately 4 hours&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ensure the stability and performance of our system,
we are performing this upgrade during the weekend
which is our period of lowest usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this maintenance window, documentation will still be serving
but new documentation builds will not trigger and the Read the Docs dashboard will not be available.
New builds and webhooks will begin processing once the maintenance is over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are moving our service to our new home on Microsoft Azure
who have generously provided us with credits to support open source software.
Some of the features we are most excited to take advantage of with this move are
managed services for Postgres and Redis as well as improvements to file storage.
This should simplify our operations considerably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank Rackspace for sponsoring our hosting for over 4 years.
They were a large supporter of open source,
and Read the Docs wouldn’t be what it is today without them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone for your support and understanding!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/2018/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Read the Docs Public API</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/api-v2/</id>
    <updated>2018-08-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-08-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/api-v2/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;read-the-docs-public-api&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, we revamped Read the Docs’ public API.
Previously, our latest API (v2) was used by our build processes
but not heavily used by outside users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of this process, we put effort into making sure the API is easy to use
to access Read the Docs &lt;em&gt;projects&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;builds&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;versions&lt;/em&gt;,
easier to filter builds and versions by a particular project,
and that the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/api/v2.html&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; is up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;deprecation-of-api-v1-and-connecting-over-insecure-http&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Deprecation of API v1 and connecting over insecure HTTP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of this process, we are formally deprecating support for our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/api/v1.html&quot;&gt;API v1&lt;/a&gt;.
It will be &lt;strong&gt;supported through at least January 1, 2019&lt;/strong&gt;
but we strongly encourage all users to migrate to API v2 at their earliest convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, both API v1 and API v2 allowed connecting over insecure HTTP
as opposed to HTTPS. &lt;strong&gt;Beginning in January 2019, we will be redirecting requests over HTTP to HTTPS.&lt;/strong&gt;
This will improve security and allow us to add more security related features to the API going forward.
For most users, this should be a one line change to connect to the HTTPS version of the API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;get-in-touch&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Get in touch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are always interested in the amazing things people create when data is openly shared.
In addition, we are always looking in improve our API to enable more projects and mashups.
If you use Read the Docs’ public API for your project
or there are additional features you’d like to see in it,
we would love to &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:team&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;readthedocs&amp;#46;org&quot;&gt;hear from you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/2018/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Do Not Track at Read the Docs</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/do-not-track/</id>
    <updated>2018-06-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-06-08T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/do-not-track/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;do-not-track-at-read-the-docs&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we are pleased to announce that Read the Docs honors &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://allaboutdnt.com/&quot;&gt;Do Not Track&lt;/a&gt; (DNT).
DNT is a browser preference that requests that a user not be tracked
across the internet while browsing the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there isn’t a consensus on precisely what DNT should mean,
we are following the Electronic Frontier Foundation’s (EFF) &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/issues/do-not-track&quot;&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt;
for Do Not Track as we believe that gives a good balance
between the privacy expectations of users and the reality of running a business
and keeping Read the Docs sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;what-we-implemented&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What we implemented&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much needed to change to make Read the Docs support DNT
and many of these changes were already necessary
for the EU’s new &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../gdpr-what-it-means-for-readthedocs/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;privacy regulation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a brief list of what we did for Do Not Track:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our logs that store any personal data are deleted after no more than ten days.
We do this for all users even those who don’t have DNT enabled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a user has DNT enabled, we do not send data to our analytics.
Based on our initial data, this looks like about a 6% reduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While this didn’t change, we reiterated that we &lt;strong&gt;do not&lt;/strong&gt;
do behavioral ad targeting regardless of DNT preference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full details on Do Not Track at Read the Docs can be found in our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/privacy-policy.html#do-not-track&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;what-dnt-means-for-our-advertising&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What DNT means for our advertising&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertising at Read the Docs was already built with privacy in mind.
With our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/stable/advertising/ethical-advertising.html&quot; title=&quot;(in Read the Docs v5.25.0)&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;xref std std-doc&quot;&gt;Ethical Ads&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we previously committed to not tracking users,
not selling user data, and hosting ads ourselves
which all align perfectly with Do Not Track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our support for DNT formalizes our commitment to the high standards
for privacy produced by the EFF.
It also make us one of very few ad networks that honor Do Not Track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;the-ethical-ad-network&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Ethical Ad Network&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../ethical-advertising-works/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
we mentioned that we are taking the same developer-centric, privacy-focused
advertising we have on Read the Docs and expanding this to a larger ad network
for open source infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supporting Do Not Track is an important milestone along the way
as it confirms our commitment to privacy in advertising.
We believe that ads don’t have to track people to be effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ethicalads.io/&quot;&gt;Ethical Ad network&lt;/a&gt; is still in its early stages,
but if you want to know more or you know a project that could use it,
please &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:ads&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;readthedocs&amp;#46;org&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/2018/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">GDPR: What it means for Read the Docs</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/gdpr-what-it-means-for-readthedocs/</id>
    <updated>2018-05-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-05-25T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/gdpr-what-it-means-for-readthedocs/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;gdpr-what-it-means-for-read-the-docs&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your email inbox has probably been bombarded
over the last few days and weeks with “Updates to our Privacy Policy”.
These emails pertain to an EU law called the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)
which comes into effect today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of the GDPR is to put users back in control of their data.
It is an important step toward respecting users’ privacy.
The days of collecting as much data on as many people as possible
without consent and sharing it with anyone willing to pay for it are over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;what-changed-at-read-the-docs&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What changed at Read the Docs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the Docs takes privacy seriously (would any company publicly say otherwise) and
relatively little changed for us as a result of the GDPR.
We intentionally don’t collect much personal information and we only do it with consent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, we did use the GDPR as an excuse to get our data house in order so to speak.
Here are a few key points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;A brand new privacy policy&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Read the Docs added a new &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/privacy-policy.html&quot;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;
that explains the data we collect, from which users we collect it, and why.
It enumerates third parties we use for various services and what data we share.
The policy also details the data we keep and when it is deleted.
Our goal was to make it easy to understand so please give it a read!&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Privacy by default&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;The GDPR mandates “data protection by design and by default”.
For us, this meant reducing the scope and duration of the logs and other data we keep.
We attempt to collect as little as possible from users merely browsing Read the Docs.
When we do collect data, such as when a user creates an account, we protect it.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;No difference for EU residents vs. everyone else&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Read the Docs applied the stricter protections mandated by the GDPR to all our users.
We believe that is the right thing to do. Creating two classes of users
and only protecting them when required by law just doesn’t seem right.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Read the Docs is committed to making sure we comply with the GDPR,
we aren’t just doing the minimum needed.
We are taking some additional steps to protect users which we will cover in a future post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;ethical-ads&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ethical Ads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguably the GDPR is a response to pernicious &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;http://blogs.harvard.edu/doc/2018/05/12/gdpr/&quot;&gt;privacy violations by advertising firms&lt;/a&gt;
so it makes sense to discuss the advertising we show on Read the Docs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Read the Docs is an ad-supported website,
we didn’t need to make any changes to our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/ethical-advertising.html&quot;&gt;Ethical Ads&lt;/a&gt; to comply with the GDPR.
That’s because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our advertising is &lt;strong&gt;well-targeted without being personal&lt;/strong&gt;.
We ensure our ads are relevant by keeping them developer focused.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethical Ads are &lt;strong&gt;hosted by Read the Docs&lt;/strong&gt;, not advertisers or a third party network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We &lt;strong&gt;don’t share personal data&lt;/strong&gt; with advertisers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By enforcing privacy by default, the GDPR shifts the discussion on advertising.
We want to create an advertising model that is a win for all parties especially users.
We know from our experience that &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../ethical-advertising-works/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;ethical advertising works&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
It is possible to make money without giving away your users data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about Ethical Ads at Read the Docs, please &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;mailto:ads&amp;#37;&amp;#52;&amp;#48;readthedocs&amp;#46;org&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;system-message&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;system-message-title&quot;&gt;System Message: INFO/1 (&lt;tt class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;/Users/lienxiong/workspace/blog/gdpr-what-it-means-for-readthedocs.rst&lt;/tt&gt;, line 78); &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#id1&quot;&gt;backlink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Duplicate implicit target name: “ethical ads”.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/2018/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Update on Ad Blocking and Acceptable Ads</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/ad-blocker-update/</id>
    <updated>2018-05-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-05-21T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/ad-blocker-update/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;update-on-ad-blocking-and-acceptable-ads&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, we shared about the
&lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../ads-and-adblocking/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;challenge ad blocking presented to our sustainability&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
and what we were doing about it.
On May 4th, Read the Docs was added to the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://acceptableads.com/&quot;&gt;Acceptable Ads list&lt;/a&gt;
meaning that our visitors running ad blockers who choose to allow unintrusive advertising
will see our ads again.
The &lt;strong&gt;impact to our ad views, clicks, and revenue was immediate&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;data-on-our-inclusion-in-the-acceptable-ads-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Data on our inclusion in the Acceptable Ads list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure align-default&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Impact of ad blocking and acceptable ads at Read the Docs&quot; src=&quot;img/2018-readthedocs-adblocker-update.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;docutils&quot;&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;32% of Read the Docs visitors run an ad blocker&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Estimates around the web vary regarding what percentage of people
run ad blockers and it varies heavily by industry.
We discussed this figure a bit in our &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../ads-and-adblocking/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;It took a month from application to inclusion in the list&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p&gt;We discovered about our inclusion in the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://easylist.to/&quot;&gt;EasyList&lt;/a&gt; ad blocker list
within a couple days and immediately applied to the Acceptable Ads program.
No changes were required of us to meet the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://acceptableads.com/en/about/criteria&quot;&gt;Acceptable Ads criteria&lt;/a&gt;
and we also qualified for &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://adblockplus.org/en/acceptable-ads#privacy-friendly-acceptable-ads&quot;&gt;Acceptable Ads without third-party tracking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Eyeo, the company behind AdBlock Plus,
derives &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://adblockplus.org/about#monetization&quot;&gt;most of their revenue&lt;/a&gt; from the Acceptable Ads initiative
by charging large entities,
Read the Docs &lt;strong&gt;did not&lt;/strong&gt; pay for inclusion on the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Over half of those running an ad blocker allow acceptable ads&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;Given our more tech-savvy and privacy-focused audience,
we didn’t know what to expect.
Not every ad blocker allows acceptable ads by default
and even then users can choose to turn them off.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;People running ad blockers DO click on ads&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;dd&gt;We can definitively say this is true of our audience.
Our click-through rate did not change based on ad blocking or
our inclusion in the acceptable ads list at all.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the ad views and clicks blocked by ad blockers,
inclusion in the Acceptable Ads list meant that 55-60%
of our ad-blocking visitors choose to allow our ads.
This directly translated into revenue toward our sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;building-our-ethical-ads&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Building our Ethical Ads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Acceptable Ads list is definitely a step in the right direction for us.
We share the goal of unintrusive advertising that respects our audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People understand that advertising funds much of the web.
As ads got larger, more annoying,
and ad networks stored more information on millions of people, however,
many people finally decided to install ad blockers.
This is the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-graph/how-to-reverse-publisher-revenue-drain-c33e41bf0665&quot;&gt;largest boycott in human history&lt;/a&gt; and blaming users isn’t the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on our experience with ad blocking and the Acceptable Ads list,
it is clear that visitors will allow advertising that doesn’t disrupt user experience
and doesn’t track people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are glad to have made progress toward regaining our sustaining revenue.
Read the Docs is continuing on our experiment to fund open source infrastructure
in a way that is a win/win for all parties,
and we are glad you’re following along with us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/2018/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Social Version Control Log in</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/version-control-login/</id>
    <updated>2018-05-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-05-17T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/version-control-login/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;social-version-control-log-in&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we are announcing the ability to log in or sign up to Read the Docs
with your favorite version control hosting services like GitHub, BitBucket, or GitLab.
This was one of our most requested features and
it has been something we’ve been meaning to launch for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;for-new-read-the-docs-users&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For new Read the Docs users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For new users, the sign up process is significantly streamlined.
There’s no new password to remember and when you’re ready to start building your docs,
Read the Docs will be ready with a list of your repositories to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the “Sign Up” button on the Read the Docs home page and then click
the button for your favorite version control hosting service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;for-existing-read-the-docs-users&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For existing Read the Docs users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve already connected your GitHub, BitBucket or GitLab account,
you can use it to log in with Read the Docs instead of your password.
If you haven’t connected your account previously,
you will have to log in normally and connect your account to use it to log in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can always see and manage which accounts you have connected
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.org/accounts/social/connections/&quot;&gt;in your profile&lt;/a&gt; (log in required).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, if you notice anything strange with your build,
feel free to raise an issue on our &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rtfd/readthedocs.org/issues&quot;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="https://blog.readthedocs.com/archive/2018/atom.xml">
    <title type="text">Ads and Ad blockers</title>
    <id>https://blog.readthedocs.com/ads-and-adblocking/</id>
    <updated>2018-05-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <published>2018-05-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <link href="https://blog.readthedocs.com/ads-and-adblocking/" />
    <author>
      <name>David Fischer</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;ads-and-ad-blockers&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last time, we shared how &lt;a class=&quot;reference internal&quot; href=&quot;../../ethical-advertising-works/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;doc&quot;&gt;ethical advertising works&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
to keep Read the Docs sustainable without creepy ad targeting.
This time, we will share about one of our biggest challenges with advertising.
At the beginning of April, Read the Docs was added to one of the most popular
ad block lists: the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://easylist.to/&quot;&gt;Easylist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;ad-blocker-fallout&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ad blocker fallout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;figure align-default&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;Effect of ad blocking on Read the Docs ad views&quot; src=&quot;img/2018-readthedocs-adblocker-fallout.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting added to the EasyList had a significant and immediate impact
on the bottom line at Read the Docs.
Right around April 1, &lt;strong&gt;32% of our ad views simply vanished&lt;/strong&gt;.
At first, we thought we had done something horribly wrong
but then we discovered that this was due entirely to ad blocking.
Our actual traffic wasn’t down at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users’ browsers were simply downloading the updated EasyList
which blocked ads on Read the Docs.
In terms of ad viewership, weekdays
– our busiest days and the peaks in the graph –
became more like weekends and weekends fell off a cliff.
We had always guessed what percentage of our user base ran ad blockers.
Now we know. We knew this day would come as we became more successful
but we had hoped it was a ways off considering we weren’t part of a large ad network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This directly affected our operations and staff.
Our operating costs didn’t go down in any significant way, but revenue sure did.
Advertising is by far the largest source of revenue at Read the Docs
and it just dropped by about a third.
This meant that we had to cut some costs where we could and slow down some hiring plans.
While Read the Docs is not a non-profit company,
all the revenue is reinvested into the project itself, paying maintainers,
and other places in the open source ecosystem.
The situation is not dire by any means,
but it was certainly disappointing that we ended up on the same list
with popup advertisers who couldn’t care less about privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;all-about-ad-blockers&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;All about ad blockers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ad blockers fulfill a legitimate need to mitigate the
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/ethical-advertising.html#ethical-info&quot;&gt;significant downsides of advertising&lt;/a&gt; from tracking across the internet,
security implications of third-party code,
and impacting the UX and performance of sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Read the Docs, we specifically didn’t want those things.
That’s why we built the ad network we wanted to exist with
only relevant ads and no creepy behavioral targeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://pagefair.com/downloads/2017/01/PageFair-2017-Adblock-Report.pdf&quot;&gt;2017 report from PageFair&lt;/a&gt; (pdf),
a company that specializes in quantifying ad blocking,
11% of global web users run an ad blocker.
Considering that Read the Docs’ core audience is tech-savvy,
privacy-conscious developers,
it should be no surprise that our number is higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;what-are-we-doing-about-it&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What are we doing about it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be an uphill battle to get back to where we were in terms of revenue
and sustaining Read the Docs, here are a few things we are working on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;simple&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We applied to the &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://acceptableads.com/&quot;&gt;acceptable ads&lt;/a&gt; list,
an ad block list enabled on many ad blockers by default
that enables some unobtrusive advertising.
We are very hopeful here but it does take quite a bit longer
to get on this list than it does to get blocked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nagging users into allowing ads on Read the Docs.
We are envisioning more of a polite nag in a similar vein to &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://jsfiddle.net/&quot;&gt;jsfiddle&lt;/a&gt;
rather than an “adblock wall” which prevents usage of Read the Docs
until it’s allowed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogging and raising awareness of how ad blocking affects us and other
open source projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we could simply change our CSS and ad API to avoid blocking
since we host our ads ourselves,  we decided not to engage in a cat and mouse game
since this work would not benefit users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertising funds much of the web and many people recognize
that while there are plenty of bad actors in the ad industry
– think pop-under ad networks or ads that navigate your browser for you –
some advertising is necessary to power the web we know and love
especially when it comes to open source software which has
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fordfoundation.org/library/reports-and-studies/roads-and-bridges-the-unseen-labor-behind-our-digital-infrastructure/&quot;&gt;unique funding challenges&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: On May 4th, Read the Docs was added to the acceptable ads list!
We will collect data over the next couple weeks and have a follow-up post
on what effects this had on advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot; id=&quot;open-source-advertising-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Open source advertising list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Read the Docs, we also discovered that we are not the only open source project
that got our advertising blocked by ad blockers.
Many open source projects that fund themselves
through advertising get blocked
and some of them don’t have the resources to navigate the acceptable ads program
or understand the inner workings of ad blockers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, some web users may not want to allow all acceptable ads
which includes many ads from the big networks but we are hoping they would be
willing to accept ads that benefit their community of software developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are launching a &lt;strong&gt;new initiative&lt;/strong&gt; to
&lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://ads-for-open-source.readthedocs.io&quot;&gt;allow advertising that benefits open source software&lt;/a&gt;. We encourage
you to subscribe to the this list and support open source.
If you run an open source project affected by ad blockers, we would love to help you too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;admonition-advertisers admonition&quot;&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;first admonition-title&quot;&gt;Advertisers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;last&quot;&gt;If you are an advertiser interested in reaching a 100% developer
audience who cares deeply about privacy,
we would love to &lt;a class=&quot;reference external&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.org/sustainability/advertising/&quot;&gt;hear from you&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
